Hehehehehehehehe!
Why did everything shake?
Why did the egg fall down and crack?
I don't understand what just happened there.
But it was awesome.
I'm gonna try that again.
Holy shit.
I think if I grab the egg and I release it, he's gonna be my friend.
I wanna race him as one of my own.
You're gonna- Oh, if I find the worm, aphrodisiac, whatever.
Whatever.
The fucking thing.
Then I will try and put that on myself.
Excuse me?
You come with me.
Let me just take a peek in here.
Just a... I have an idea.
What if we say fuck the gods.
It's a big one.
It's a big gun.
What the fuck?
Why is it so big?
Is it orange?
It's eating.
Oh.
It ate the diamond brickwork.
Sir, where did you go?
Oh, I'm scared.
No, how am I not dead?
How did that not just kill me?
Okay, so he's not my... Oh, maybe he is my friend.
I didn't take damage.
He has an HP bar.
Whoa.
Take through the tree.
Take to the other side.
I need to get through.
I need to see what's there.
Come on.
What are you doing?
And he's
off.
Is he coming back?
My screen is shaking.
He's going to come back, isn't he?
In full force.
I want to see what's on the other side.
What do we got in here?
Okay, nothing there.
I like his handwriting here.
It's very nice.
Where did you go, sir?
Oh my God.
He's digging everywhere.
Oopsy daisy.
You know what?
I'm just going to let him do his thing.
Yeah.
Fuck it.
Just do your thing.
I'm moving on.
I'm going to do my thing, which is just explore like normal.
You can do whatever it is you want.
We've got enemies down there.
Dude, I have all this knowledge now about the wands.
I can probably make a super sick wand real quick.
I know a bunch of spells now.
It's the mines.
Wait, what kind of wand do I even have?
Energy sphere.
Oh, I like those.
Energy sphere is good.
Oh, yeah.
The damage is so good.
Come on.
There we go.
Get that gold.
Let's explode that because it's fun.
Heck yeah.
I'm going to explode that too.
I missed.
Now, you know what?
Let's not explode that.
Leave it be.
I'm only going to do that if there's gold nearby in the dirt or something that I can pick up after.
Is that you doing things?
Taking care of.
I have sick aim.
What should I call the worm?
I don't even know.
Maybe that's Matilda.
Seems like a digging name, you know?
Matilda the worm.
I wonder if she's going to show up here again.
That is toxic rock.
Can't get through there.
So I'm going to go up and right.
Come on.
In fact, let me just check what's up here on the left again.
Maybe I'll come back out at some point just to see what kind of work Matilda has been doing.
Maybe she's been digging a nice little path for me.
Wait a minute.
Where is this?
Does this even lead anywhere?
There is a wand over there that I really want to get.
I do have bombs on me.
Hold on.
Yeah, I know how to get there.
I know how to get there.
We're going to blow up that wall.
So the goal now is to get four wands at least.
Before I get to the portal.
Four wands and a bunch of money.
That's the goal.
Because if I have that, I have maximum opportunity to create something nice.
Scrip!
Wait!
It didn't blow up what I thought it would blow up.
But fire is sort of spreading and that it's probably going to eat through... I was going to say steel, but that's not going to happen, is it?
Enemies are dying at least.
It's eating through the wood.
That's good.
Will it eat through the ground?
Whoa!
Okay, it will.
Awesome!
I have an access point.
Maybe I'll just wait a bit for this to calm down in case there is more going on.
Are we calm?
Be calm, Yolanda.
What is that?
Oh, that thing's going to explode, isn't it?
We got a wand with an energy sphere.
I'll take it.
May as well do it.
Let's see here.
Okay, my first one is better.
It shoots faster.
It's a good start though.
78 monies in the bank.
I have two more bombs to work with in case I need to get somewhere.
I'm actually so happy that this one bomb triggered this whole series of explosions that inevitably, or not inevitably, but ultimately led to the opening up of that area for me.
Very fortunate.
A bit of luck there.
This dude.
Shotgun man.
Okay, this bounces off walls.
What a dodge.
Give me that money.
Need to kill this guy down here before I forget about him and die to him later.
Yo!
Extra max HP!
Fuck yeah!
Where'd he go?
He's blowing up something.
He's on a mission.
So am I.
A mission for riches and a grand adventure.
There's a fire in my heart.
Hey guys, it's a fire mage.
Uh-oh.
Gotcha.
Give me that gold.
Another one there.
Gotcha.
Give me that gold.
I'm scared.
I hit him.
Yoink!
I'm on fire.
There we go.
Nice.
I am so scared of this dude.
He died!
Yo, he was on fire!
I thought he would somehow be immune to that.
Flamoxium potion.
I think I should try and put that on the enemies, because it definitely doesn't work well on me.
Hold on, is this a trap somehow?
I don't think so.
What do we got?
Double spell, double spell.
Sparkly bounce.
Makes a projectile release damaging sparks as it bounces.
Black hole.
A slow orb of void that eats through all obstacles.
What?
Charm on toxic sludge.
Makes a projectile charm creature covered in toxic sludge.
Makes a projectile...
charm creatures.
Okay, I understand, I understand.
Sure, let's try that.
Uh, drip.
Oh!
What's up Matilda?
Hello?
Let me try that again.
Wait, actually?
Oh!
This is insane!
Oh wait, I don't have infinite.
Fuck!
I don't have infinite.
I need to save this.
Oh no, I was used to infinity.
The infinity game style.
Oh, look at this!
Awesome!
But wait, there's also another one over here, isn't there?
That's crazy!
Uh, where was it?
Somewhere over here.
So it seems like Matilda is just somewhere in the level.
Digging.
And that's kind of awesome.
Motherfucker.
Come here!
Yeah!
Round and corner, round and corner.
There we go, here we go.
I will actually not use the black hole.
I'm gonna do that.
What a cool spell!
Oh wait, it doesn't go through that though!
Oh wait, it burns, it burns, it burns.
We're fine.
It's gonna work.
Gotcha.
There's gold, I'll take it.
That's mine.
Can I reach that somehow?
Shit.
Well, that was a waste of a bomb.
So I guess I'll have to do this.
Hoi!
Yo, that's so good!
Oh, oh, hello, hello.
I wonder if it'll eat through enemies as well.
Whoa, what happened?
Everything's shaking.
Is that Matilda doing things?
Matilda, don't approach me.
I know you like to do your thing.
Oh, we've gotta want...
Disc projectile.
This is actually kind of cool as well.
20 damage is nothing to scoff at.
You know?
Three degrees, capacity six, spells cast one.
I don't know.
250 mana max, mana charge speed.
No, I think this one is way better.
I don't like this.
Cancel!
I say no to that.
I refuse.
What happens if I shoot a wand?
Okay, nothing.
Can I kick a wand?
Okay, it's sort of a magical item, which makes sense.
Dynamite and that thing scares me.
So I'm gonna do this.
Oh, shit.
That's for you, sir.
There we go.
For some reason, he didn't throw any dynamite.
Makes me happy.
Oh, that's not good.
Let's not do that.
I can't get over how cool that black hole was.
Imagine having infinite of that.
What a life that would be.
And there's a chance we could get that.
If we get the right perk...
Actually, money solves all problems.
If we don't get the right perk, we can reroll them with enough money.
So all we need is money.
Money, money, money.
This could be insane.
Slime potion?
Right.
Slime potion.
Yeah, let me up.
Can't get through there.
What's happening up here?
Why is everything so toxic?
Oh, this is the entrance.
Oh, I don't remember things being this toxic when I came in.
Wow, you fast jumper.
What was that thing I just killed here?
Hey, dude.
I'm coming up.
Stay put.
I'm not coming up.
Forever.
Let's see what's over here.
Oh, is that another way up?
Perfect.
Gotcha.
And that's a dent.
Good.
But it's money in the pocket.
And that's important.
Exploration pays off so much in this game.
The fact that I found the extra HP and black hole shit.
Awesome.
That's another polymorphine potion.
But it's not chaotic.
So that's going to make me a sheep.
Gunpowder potion?
Huh?
Wait, I thought gunpowder was in a bag.
It's a powder.
The fuck?
Wait a minute.
Drink this.
Oh, it's not good.
I puke.
I lose HP.
Douse.
Oh, I'm poisoned real bad.
Oh, that was a bad idea.
I guess it makes sense.
Why would you drink gunpowder?
I don't want polymorphine.
Unless!
You can throw that on enemies and it will make them into a sheep and you can one hit them.
Imagine that.
Nah, probably another thing.
I feel like I tried to polymorph enemies.
Didn't work.
But maybe I just need to try more.
Maybe there's different thresholds.
Because for me, it seems like the threshold is very low.
Who's doing that?
It's you.
Stop it.
And we've got a dude down here.
Hubby!
God, I love the exploration.
I love the feeling of finding upgrades and shit.
I just love roguelikes.
Oh, what is this?
Oh, we're almost at the surface.
Speaking of the surface.
Kind of want to go back up there.
Also, where's Matilda?
What's she up to?
Matilda?
Wait, is this the... that's lava, isn't it?
Got you.
You ain't shit.
Uh, can't even get through there.
That's interesting.
Let's see what's in here.
Is that toxic?
Oh, that is definitely toxic.
Get up here.
I'm exploring everything.
Whoa!
Damn!
Lovely how the music starts after that.
Oh, that's toxic.
That's toxic.
Douse!
53 HP.
Douse it.
Okay.
Enemies?
Where'd you go?
Got them.
Bunch of explosives in there.
That's tempting.
Yeah.
Oh, I thought everything.
Oh, okay.
There we go.
That's the explosion I was looking for.
And that's the portal.
I see the outline.
Okay.
Good to know.
It's there.
Oh man.
Look at all these guys.
It's a little congregation there.
What you guys up to?
See ya.
Gold for me.
That was... 400 gold is what I have now.
That's... Oh, there's another portal here.
Entered Holy Mountain.
Has that text ever appeared like that?
Look at this guy.
He has a... he's about to have a bad day.
A very bad day.
Have fun.
Game of that gold.
Nice.
I want to... I want to keep exploring.
I'm playing very greedy here.
But that's okay, because I still have... I want to say half HP, but half HP in the sense that I start with 100.
You know what I mean?
So I feel like I've used up half of my allowance and I still have half to go.
What is going on?
There's enemies.
They're covered in blood.
Explode that.
Look at all that poison.
Just draining down.
Isn't that a beautiful sight?
I think it's great.
Oh, this guy's about to have a bad day as well.
So many bad days today.
Come here.
No.
Come on.
You know you want to.
All the way.
There we go.
Hand over the money.
Ow!
Brother?
You little fucker.
He bit me.
Can't believe you bit me.
That fucking hurt.
I just wanted the part.
Nobody's going to know where that's from.
Hello.
Oh my God.
Look at that.
There's more health.
Got him.
Yoink.
And the gold.
Thank you.
What do we have down here?
Yo, what's that?
Excuse me?
What the fuck?
It's raining blood.
Hallelujah.
He made a rainy blood cloud.
That's so unfortunate, man.
So how did I die?
So, ah, he shot those little orbs that bounced everywhere and they hit me.
Look.
No, wait.
I died from an explosion.
So, the explosion happened here.
Oh, there's some kind of electricity explosion in that as well.
Ah, man.
I put myself in a terrible position going down there.
I should have gone up here instead.
That's what I should have done.
Don't go towards the unknown when you want to flee.
Go back from whence you came.
That's a good rule, I think.
Man, that was such a good start, though.
That was such a cool start.
Matilda and everything?
The black hole and shit?
Aw, man.
What's this?
Swamp potion.
This time we're not gonna drink it.
Wait a minute.
What the hell is this?
Unstable crystal.
A crystal that explodes when someone comes nearby.
A hundred.
Damn.
Does it work on me?
Oh, it totally does.
Swamp water.
So, that's a bad start.
That's what we in the biz call a bad start.
Can I just immediately new game?
Now I know.
That was the fastest run yet.
But now I know.
We have an unstable crystal again.
Keep going.
Now I know what it does.
Okay.
What is the first one?
Bouncing burst.
How is that one?
Right.
Man, it bounces a lot.
I like it.
I like the bounce.
Why did that go backwards?
What are the chances of that
whoa there's another one somewhere right wasn't there another one the hell is this
hold on release it there's some kind of thing down there look what is that is that just this it just looks like a like there's a pattern on it somehow okay maybe not let's get out again Ah, no!
Swap water.
It's not swamp water, it's acceler... whoa!
Acceleration.
Holy shit.
Yo, that's nice.
Look at that!
Damn.
Oh, that's a trap.
That is a trap.
Blop.
Hey!
That's how we do it in Kansas.
You may wonder at times, why do they do it like that in Kansas?
I don't know, they just do.
They just do.
Wait a minute, is this still... I don't trust this one?
Oh, never mind.
So what is this?
Digging bolt.
A bolt that is ideal for mining.
Okay, but how does it work?
Yeah, look, it triggered it.
Oh!
Oh, it's totally mining.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Somewhat?
It's not that effective, is it?
I mean, it goes through this, but it doesn't go through that.
Okay.
Interesting, so it actually just does exactly what it says.
That's a huge barrel.
Are they brewing beer?
Oh my god, it's leaking.
Is that actually beer?
Drink it.
I can't... what is it?
Heavy scent of booze, oozes of your clothes.
Aiming is disturbed, and alcohol is flammable.
I'm drunk.
I can't believe that's a thing.
Yeah, you're in oil, buddy.
Why would you throw that in there?
That's a dumb idea.
Now you're gonna burn alive.
Are you not?
I think he died.
Wait, this is not water.
This is acceleration potion.
Let's not accelerate the fire anymore.
Dead end.
What's over here?
See, this part is very similar always.
I think certain parts of these levels are very similar always, but then the rest is... oh my god, I'm so fast.
Dang.
I'm gonna do this.
That should get me through.
Hit it.
Oh no.
Run around!
Okay.
Oh shit.
This is so cool.
The fact that all of this is simulated is mind-blowing to me.
Like, you could mistake this game for being super simple when you look at it initially, but...
It's actually super complex.
Got him.
Look at all that blood that just emanated from such a tiny creature.
We've got a flaming skull and 46 bucks.
Man, we haven't made any money yet.
And no wands.
Up, up, up, up.
Damn.
Oh, that's a poison.
That's a wand.
Puff of smoke.
Burst of air, I mean.
Greatly, greatly pushing objects, though.
Fuck it.
We take that.
Can I push enemies?
Oh, that did damage?
Yo!
I feel like I've been sleeping on this.
Hello?
Wait a minute, does it say damage?
It does say... I didn't even notice.
I assumed it would be no damage.
I just assumed because it was burst of air.
Wow, okay.
Hello.
Burst of air.
Not bad.
Oh, it's pushing the gold.
Damn.
And I also know that if you shoot this through fire, it's gonna be a burst of fire air.
This is a great wand!
And there's more.
The arrow.
Only... Oh, damage slice five.
So this one goes through enemies, right?
Just like the saw blade thingy?
What about the thingy?
Oh, this is a crazy small castor lay, isn't it?
Six degrees, mana max.
Hmm.
I don't think I want this one.
Let me try this.
Yo!
Hello?
Okay, it doesn't go through them, but The rate of fire on this?
Hello, that's insane.
Yeah, yeah, me likey.
Then we have stuff like this.
Circle of shielding, a field of protective magic.
Well, I...
How protective is it?
Oh!
Sick!
And I can shoot out of it.
Yo!
That could come in hella handy.
Not bad at all.
Fuck yeah.
I'm gonna experiment with that.
We're gonna try all the spells.
Accelerant.
Oh, yeah, collapsed mines is also a thing.
I didn't get there last time, I don't think.
Let's arrow these fools.
Oh my god, I'm so quick.
Relatively straight arc as well.
Well, is it actually completely straight?
No, not quite.
It still arcs a little bit.
That looks like some kind of poison?
No, concentrated mana.
I knew it.
That was gonna happen.
I fucking knew it.
I knew it.
Holy shit!
That was an unfortunate combination of happenstances.
Oh my god, I got hit in the face.
Again!
This is unreal.
It's going terribly.
Don't even hit me, sir.
Man, I sliced him in half.
Yo, that looks awesome.
Looks like a bow.
Uh, does it matter how it looks at all, Firebolt?
Not actually that great.
I'll leave it.
Don't want it, don't need it.
It's a frog, it's dead.
What is this thing right here?
Runestone of weight.
Why is there a happy smiley on it?
A runestone with a strong magical aura.
You feel like kicking it.
Oh, yeah?
Do I now?
Uh...
What?
Yeah, what's happening?
Is this damaging enemies?
And now it stops!
So you can kick it into activation mode.
Huh.
The hell?
Oh, hello.
Wow, that's an enemy?
I thought it was just like a little critter, like the scorpions we saw.
Okay.
Right in the face.
Oh, okay, it's just water, right?
Got him.
Man, this arrow is actually nuts.
I like this weapon.
Salt pouch!
A handy pouch.
Okay, yeah, so salt, huh?
Huh.
Man, I...
How do I mix these chemicals?
There's definitely a way to do some kind of chemical mixing.
Like, why would there be salts and all these other powders?
If you couldn't do anything with it.
And you can't go halfway, apparently.
You got to go all the way.
Shook one's part two, basically.
Here?
Let's go here.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Very good.
I can get through here, I think.
Um...
Let's use the unstable crystal.
Jupsey!
Unstable.
Fuck yeah.
Actually insane.
Uh...
What the hell is that?
Oh, it's just dirt.
Never mind.
It looks very different.
For a second there.
So there's a path here.
What was that?
Please let this go somewhere.
Don't let me die.
Okay.
Ooh.
Fuck yeah.
I found...
A wand.
With TNT.
16 uses and blood mist.
Okay.
Manamax 380.
Dude, Manamax 380, isn't that a lot?
If I find a holy hand grenade, I could use this.
Dude.
Maybe I'll just replace this one.
It's gonna TNT anyway, and fuck this one, I guess.
Yeah, I'll take it.
Neat!
In fact, maybe I'll dig through here, because there's stuff on the other side.
But that is a... Wait, why does it only say 10?
This is gonna be risky.
Run!
Okay.
Thank God.
We did it.
Wow, they bounce!
Oh yeah.
Not bad at all.
Lovely stuff.
217 gold.
Concentrated mana.
I'll take it, sure.
I guess...
If I really need to use a lot of mana, I can drink that.
And everything is fine, or douse myself in it.
Whoa!
Don't jump at me.
I somehow hit a guy in the back as well.
I didn't even see him.
Oh, that's the trap from before.
It's still sort of just emitting on its own.
Mushrooms!
End of the road.
Did I check what's up here?
Let's go this way.
People are exploding.
What is that?
Something there.
Oh, it's just a flower, I think.
We've got steam.
That means explosions have happened right here.
Hey.
You want some?
In fact, let me take care of your friend first.
Got him.
Fire is spreading.
That means I can get through here now.
Let's go this way first.
Yeah, it's the same path.
Uh-oh!
Those are insane.
I think I got him.
Let's grab that money.
Sick.
Copper in there.
Nice!
So smooth, man.
I'm getting good at the combat.
And then we have this fucking thing again.
Is it the same?
It is Mardina.
So this is about the gold and silver.
Okay, I'm gonna go on to the other side of the lava here now.
And then I'm gonna try and see if I... Oh, hold on.
With accelerant.
Maybe I can really go quick.
Hold on a second.
Oh, fuck yeah!
That is awesome.
So I'm wondering what's below this bridge.
Maybe we should check that out, too.
It's gonna collapse, I guess.
The orb room.
Is this the same tablet?
Volume 7.
Transmutation of metals.
Right.
Don't go halfway.
You're rewarded with additional health.
Fuck yeah.
And now I get the fuck out of here.
Before the boss spawns.
Run.
Run, run, run, run, run, run, run.
Shit!
Oh!
Alright.
Yeah, I'm dead.
I'm dead.
I'm dead, dude.
I have an idea.
Yo, you like this?
Yo, it's using a wand, look?
Holy fuck!
Accelerant, accelerate.
Go!
Accelerate me, accelerate me.
What do we have down here?
Watch below, watch below.
Come on.
Holy shit, they're steep.
I'm afraid the boss is gonna come down here.
Yo, where the fuck are we?
I can't get up again, by the way.
I'm stuck here.
Whoa!
Oh!
Sneapooheasy.
You motherfucker.
Okay, okay, okay.
So that looked like the snowy region.
Is that a shortcut to the snowy region?
Because that would be insane as well.
Wait a minute, what do we have?
Magic missile, hold on.
Isn't that the one that...
Yeah, I'm going this way now.
Watch, I can do this.
Oh wait, what?
Oh, I need mana, mana.
And then I can rest there.
I'm going this path again.
I did this once before.
But I was very new and I had no idea what was going on.
But now I'm very experienced and I have no idea what's going on.
But I have a little bit more of an idea what's going on.
So what the hell is... what's all this snow here?
Hold on, is there a secret in the snow?
I don't know, maybe.
Maybe if you dig deep enough, there's a secret.
I seem to remember me finding an orb somewhere down here as well, if I'm not crazy.
Oh, there's enemies in there.
Those are the mines.
What did I just hear?
Oh look, fish.
Ah, there's this thing down here.
What the hell is the deal?
With that?
Like, what is that even?
Looks like a musical instrument.
Some kind of fucked up alien musical instrument.
That I can't quite explain.
I need accelerant right here.
What's that?
Oh, just a little piece of snow.
No wait, that's a mushroom.
A blue mushroom.
Here we go.
It's desert time.
Enter the desert.
So weird that you can... the air feels hot.
They can just go up here, you know?
Also, this one is kind of... what is happening here?
Why is it saying... up, down?
There's got to be something here.
What if I...
blow it up?
Oh, this needs a long recharge.
This is actually insane.
Why does it need so long?
Oh, nine mana charge speed.
Holy shit.
That is... okay, you know what?
That's not... it's not doing anything.
Ah, let me try at least.
Now I'm committed.
Let me do one more.
Okay.
I somehow expected that to be simulated and fall down.
Weird that it didn't.
Given everything else in this game.
Maybe there was a single pixel still connecting it somehow that I missed.
Bone wall.
I'm tempted to cut myself in there, but what would I achieve by doing that?
That is the question we have to ask ourselves.
Oh my god.
Damn, that guy had aim.
What the hell is this?
Wait.
Square, square, three circles...
square.
Wait a minute.
These are spells!
This is the, uh, the one I had a wand with with a bunch of them, remember?
I had like this entire array with the quantum entanglement shit.
This one I'm not sure what is.
But I know this is a spell.
What is this down here?
Kind of vase.
Oh!
Spawn's little... little dudes.
Okay.
Uh, I wanna grab that.
I'm gonna grab that.
Come on.
Oh, I'm actually, I'm drinking the water and the blood.
Ah, the gold is gone.
Fuck.
Okay, that's weird.
There's a ghost.
Wait, what?
Yo, does he have, he has an aura of confusion?
That's what I just felt.
My character moved opposite.
Fuck yeah, we're going in there.
Open up!
There we go!
Show me what you got.
Oh no, I'm confused again.
Oh, this is so weird.
A berserk curse affects you.
Fuck yo, vas.
Am I taking damage?
I'm not.
What the hell are these?
I just come in here and vandalize their temple or whatever.
What is happening here?
There's three of them.
Hello!
That's gotta be possible.
Hold on.
No!
Huh, wait a minute.
No, that's definitely not doing it.
I do have two shots left.
I could use it.
Or I can start here maybe.
I love kicking things.
Oh!
Oh shit!
Right, but you know what?
Motherfucker.
It's actually a great source of money.
Come out!
Uh...
Blue sand.
Eat it.
Eat the blue sand.
This is very intriguing.
Hello.
Oh, that's acid!
It burns through things!
Cool!
I can shoot the little projectiles as well.
Oh man, that's so awesome!
What a cool spell.
Shit!
Wow, look at all that flammable gas.
Oh my god.
We got a dude up there and something... Research notes!
Say what?
Oh my god, acid!
Oh, it's over.
It's over.
Kill him!
Oh my god, it's over!
Oh no!
That gooey acid thing had so much HP.
That was insane.
I died from material freezing vapor.
Okay.
Yeah.
Daaaang.
Well, that was fun.
Let's keep going.
I can't get enough of this.
Why is this so much fun?
No phone.
I'm not trying to tell you something.
Try Gemini.
No, go away.
Yo, can I ride this?
Let's go!
Yes, come on noble steed.
Yay!
Oh, okay.
Uh, what the hell is that?
Right, a thingy that explodes.
Why did I question it?
I think I just crit him.
Wait, what am I using?
Chaotic polymorphine.
That's actually okay.
Hell yeah, look at this.
That's for you.
Oh man, that explodes quick.
What?
Oh my god!
See, he got a polymorph into this.
Okay, it's confirmed.
You can polymorph enemies.
That was hilarious.
Damn, what the shit?
Uh, what is this?
Berserkium potion.
What does this actually do?
Hold on.
A berserk curse affects you.
It's a curse.
It's bad.
What?
Actually, it affects my...
look.
Maybe I do more damage.
Look at my spells.
It has like a weird blood effect to it now.
Like I'm some kind of blood-hungry viking.
Whatever.
Actually, you know what?
Let's try.
Douse.
Two shots.
Okay.
Let's try and see if we can find another one of these and try without the berserkium.
There's a dude up there, but I can't get to him.
I don't want to get to him.
Uh, that thing is scaring me.
So those guys need two hits from this.
I can test with those as well, I guess.
Let's test with this guy now.
One, two.
Oh, but that one crits.
Yep.
Is that gold?
It is gold.
Thank you.
That is acid potion.
Oh, but you know what?
I could do with that.
I can throw the potion.
I constantly forget that I can do that.
If I can throw that on an enemy, that would be pretty sick.
In fact, I'm gonna do it.
I'm gonna get it.
Blop.
Gain access.
Whoa, it's fiery.
Let's just hang back for a second here.
Uh, there we go.
Oh, I got it.
This thing just fell down.
A bunch of acid here.
Got him.
Grab that gold.
What the hell?
He's gonna execute the water.
Yeah, that doesn't look good.
Don't go in there.
So what do we got?
Bubble Spark.
I like those.
I like this wand.
Yo, that's good.
That's really nice.
But let me test with this again.
No crit this time.
One, two, three.
Okay.
I think it's hard to say with the Berserkium.
But it makes sense if you think about it.
Berserker rage and all that.
It's got to be damaged, right?
Let me see if I can one hit these guys now.
Oh yeah, it definitely does work.
Okay, okay.
It's confirmed.
We have confirmed the Berserkium.
100% and that was not a crit.
I'm starting to think the crit is just a random percentage chance.
It doesn't matter where you hit them.
It's just crit.
See, aiming for his head.
Nothing's happening.
Got him.
Blop.
Beer!
Oh.
I blocked my own path.
That's fucking stupid.
Shit, can I get can I get in some way else?
Oh man.
What's happening?
Something is exploding.
Uh, what just happened here?
Unstable teleportation potion.
What does unstable mean?
We gotta try it.
Drink it.
Oh!
You teleport uncontrollably every now and then.
I managed to read that in time.
That is funny.
What?
Yo, that's awesome!
That's fucking cool.
Imagine you can... Oh, it's also dangerous, I guess.
What if you get spawned right next to a pack of enemies?
That's a little bit risky, isn't it?
But it's fun.
Hello.
Yellow.
Don't hit me.
Got him.
Whoa.
Shit!
That exploded right on my face.
Oh, it's that guy!
Don't don't die now.
Don't die now.
Whoa, he died quick somehow.
It's the same enemy, isn't it?
Wait, green slimy meat.
Wait a minute.
Chainsaw.
Cuts through meat.
Maybe that's really good against these enemies.
Got him.
I don't want to go in the portal just yet.
I don't have enough money...
to buy these things that are going to be there.
And I want one more wand.
Uh, what's up, guys?
Pretty cool.
Also pretty cool.
Another portal.
Why are there so many?
Uh, there's a guy down there.
Gotcha.
I like these little guys.
They're nice.
Uh, I want to get in there.
So we're gonna have to do this.
A path has been opened.
And you're dead, sir.
Uh...
Got a whole congregation here.
Get the money!
Oh, shit!
Too greedy.
Fuck, I forgot the money disappeared.
Oh, that was a good hole though.
Got a lot of money there.
Could have been better, but it's okay.
We have a dude here.
Oh, I'm gonna kill him.
It's free money.
Gotcha.
Very good.
Soil pouch.
I need to figure out how to use these pouches.
Yo, what the hell?
Are you causing trouble?
Oh my god!
What a shot!
That exploded right in my face.
Well done, sir.
Well done.
That was, that was sick.
Watch this.
Right in front of my eyes.
Look, bam!
Dang, that's violent.
I want to save this one.
Okay, it's loading.
That's a cool death.
I like that one.
That's nice.
In fact, I should start saving all of these.
That would be fun to have like a little collection at the end.
I'm gonna start doing that.
That'll be a lot of fun.
I guess I'm technically saving everything because I'm recording, but you know still.
May as well do it.
May as well kick it.
Can I kick it?
Yes, you can.
Write it down.
Oh, that was a little bit buggy.
Up, up, up, up, up, up.
Whoa!
What a mess.
Oh my god, would you look at that?
Oh, there's a guy down there as well.
Did not even see him.
And he's dead.
I need to grab all the money up here.
Got it.
I don't know why I kick everything.
It's just satisfying.
Oh, that was close.
You know, the bounciness of this spell right here is a little bit risky too.
If it starts to hit one of those explodey barrels.
Man, that was a sick shot.
Something is, uh, why is everything shaking so much?
Is it just explosions?
Feels like more.
Is Matilda around?
I just had a great idea.
If you manage to find worm pheromone and you release the worm, you can sort of guide it.
Dude, I can spray it in a corner and it'll go there and dig for me.
Holy shit!
Circle of stillness?
Feel the freezing magic.
Yeah, I don't understand the circle of stillness, unfortunately.
That's a little, uh...
It doesn't slow projectiles.
Maybe it just slows the movement of enemies.
That could be it, you know, or they get frozen in there.
That's actually probably what happens.
Let's try it.
I did try it once, but it didn't seem to do much, but let's try again.
Oh yeah, that's right!
Okay, it's pretty good.
It's pretty good.
I take it back.
It's awesome.
That's fantastic.
Blow that up.
Why?
Because I can.
And it's fun.
I can't pass here, right?
Damn it.
Oh, come on.
Burn through.
Let me pass.
Yeah.
Oh no.
Yes.
Nope, the other way.
Okay, fine.
Uh, we've got dudes there.
Oh, that's actually so good though.
The circle of stillness.
It's doing work.
And there's like 13 uses left.
Not bad at all.
I think I'm hitting something.
Look at the way it's bouncing up again.
He was fast.
Okay, he stilled.
Oh, give me the money.
Look at all this blood.
It's a bloodbath.
Literally.
Does it want?
I want it.
Get it?
Uh, it's a trap.
But, hold on, is this trap sort of, uh, broken?
Because the whiskey's gone.
Yoink.
Yeah, look.
Whiskey's flammable, but not when there's no whiskey.
Wise words from a wise man.
Hello.
Come up here.
Shit!
Wrong spell.
Ouch.
I hit right in the face.
Come here, fucker.
Fuck you.
That's awesome.
Get the fuck out of here.
Got him?
Oh my god, I'm owning.
I wonder what the deal is.
There's copper here, right?
Is that, like, a valuable...
Can I actually do anything with that?
In the water.
We're fine.
I actually have 67 HP.
Everything is going swimmingly.
Uh, someone's throwing dynamite, I think?
Uh, someone played too much with dynamite.
And that gold belongs to me now.
Watch me bounce this.
Never mind.
Got him.
We're on fire.
Douse...
Wait, that's accelerant.
Don't douse yourself with that.
Uh...
I'm sure going here.
Ah, I'm on fire.
Oh, okay, we're fine.
Damn.
What a shit show.
But a very interesting shit show.
The poop has never been this entertaining.
Okay.
Another one.
Yank.
Oh, are we at the fire?
Oh, here we go.
Let me take that.
Okay, so I have accelerant.
That means...
We get to go fast.
Fuck yeah.
Look at me speedrunning this shit.
We're gonna go down here again.
For sure.
So, he's actually gonna appear from down there.
Grab this too.
Grab it.
Move!
Accelerant!
Holy crap!
He keeps shooting.
Accelerate.
We made it.
Are we gonna encounter another one of those dudes down here?
Hold on, what do I have?
Circle of stillness?
I have a lot of circle of stillness here.
Shit, are we gonna find another one of these fuckers?
Uh-oh.
Oh my god.
He's shooting projectiles at me.
And I'm doing no damage.
Let's not get hit by that freezing vapor.
That is dangerous.
Snowy depths!
Holy shit!
Wow!
Okay, so that means if I ever get to...
Damn!
If I ever get to snowy depths like the normal way, I could technically come back up here.
If I find it, I have to go up, I guess.
That's crazy!
Give me that money.
But how can I get back up from now?
I think I'm stuck to be here now though, and I have no weapons that are good.
That's a rock.
Oh!
What?!
Wait, are you a friend?
You're not a friend.
Uh...
Circle of stillness time.
Yo, calm down.
Oh my god.
This is bad!
Got him.
Oh!
You are still, sir!
Doesn't really affect him that much, does it?
Oh my god.
Come here!
Come here, you!
Is that another one?
Or is that the same?
Keep shooting him.
Is that what I think it is?
The Circum.
Douse time.
Shit, I missed myself completely.
That's great.
Oh my god!
Oh my lord, that's crazy!
How about we don't fuck with that?
I'm in deep shit, guys.
This is bad.
I am out of my depth here.
Well, we gotta keep going.
There's nothing else to it.
Put on a brave face.
I could also try and get back somehow.
Wait, are these projectiles being spawned?
They are being spawned, motherfucker.
Bombs for you.
Shoot that guy!
Oh my god!
Okay, I got hit by two of them at the same time.
Shit!
We gotta save this one.
Look at this broom!
They both sort of, uh...
Sandwiched me.
Bam!
One after another.
Damn.
That was brutal.
Save as gift.
Yeah, save all of it.
Well, this was good though.
Now I know we can get here quick.
And maybe there's a way to get back up as well later.
If we find some way to, I don't know, levitate forever.
Wouldn't surprise me if that's the thing.
Uh, unstable crystal and we have the energy spheres.
I love the energy spheres.
They may actually be my favorite starter ones.
And a blood potion.
A blood potion.
I want straight away.
With the magic missile!
That's a good amount of damage.
It's actually kind of crazy.
Look how simple this wand looks.
Oh, oh yeah, that's good.
Uh, this is a flower that grows vant- what the fuck is that?
It's a poisonous flower.
Let's not mess with that.
I can burn for all I care.
We don't want poison.
We do want this though.
Thank you.
What a great start.
Yo,
this is new.
Why is that here suddenly?
Hup!
Run!
Oh no!
Motherfucker, I gotta be quick.
Okay.
I see.
Kill that guy.
Shit.
Oh boy.
Oh damn.
Whoa.
See how much damage this one does.
It's so good.
Show yourself.
There we go.
We have a guy down there.
Oh, what?
Damn.
So good.
Another vine sprout.
What is this electricity shit?
He's eating it.
Don't eat the electricity.
The hell?
This is so cool.
Things are changing.
Okay.
I'm gonna go all the way to the right, grab that upgrade, and get the fuck out of there.
And I'm gonna go left again.
Hopefully the boss won't follow me.
Oh, there's water up there.
That's the surface.
Uh, shit.
I should have been quicker.
We can do this actually.
Burn in hell.
Let me through.
I demand to see your supervisor.
The boss, that is.
You know what?
I have a bunch of crazy spells.
Maybe I can take on that boss.
I have no idea how much HP he has.
It did feel like a lot that one time I tried, but...
Oh no.
Better.
We should be able to fuck you up as well.
I love that sound.
Doo doo doo doo.
Like a piece of glass bottle being thrown around or something.
This... maybe I should have gone down instead of right.
That makes more sense, I think.
Although it is sort of... no, we gotta go down.
Oh!
Fuck, that scared me.
I forgot that is also proximity-based.
Shit.
I'm an idiot.
Oh well.
Oh!
Wow!
Ow!
Fuck you, Haiku.
How...
How likko hee-see.
That probably means...
Uh...
Shotgun wearing hee-see.
Or something.
Shotgun wielding wee-see.
Hee-see.
Shit.
I forgot to save the thing.
Damn it.
Keep going.
Ah, that was such a good start though.
We found the extra HP and everything.
Difficult game.
Holy shit.
I'm just glad I had one amazing run.
So far.
Learned a lot.
Is this...
slime potion?
I do actually want to try and throw these on the enemies.
But it's just gonna cover them in slime, I guess?
Oh, hold on.
Where's that draining?
It's draining off somewhere.
I have TNT.
Drain away.
What's...
Just be careful here.
So much poison.
What the hell?
Yeah, it's not enough.
I need the purifying thing I found once.
Ah, it is actually slowly draining.
That's nice.
Okay, but there's nothing in there.
Bunch of enemies up there.
Oh, I have this wand now.
Oh no.
Ho!
Thank you!
Oh my god.
Excuse me!
Exquisite me!
What a chaotic shit show.
The enemies took care of the big guy.
That's awesome.
Then we have this.
With a torch.
I mean, sure.
May as well.
In fact, this wand right here is also very nice.
Eight damage is actually quite a lot.
Woah!
Health.
We're gonna get it.
Got him?
Uh... Oh, it's you!
Holy shit!
Bzzzah!
Come here!
Actually, I'm in a very bad spot here.
This is a bad spot to be in.
Let me open a path.
There we go.
If I can go down at least.
Holy shit.
Oh!
What the fuck?
Where'd you come from?
Where the fuck did you come from?
I feel like this run is insane.
There's so much shit happening.
So many enemies.
And also the vines.
Everything is crazy.
They're all burning.
Give me that money!
What?
Oh yeah, burn them.
Burn them all.
That guy is still alive.
Got him!
Oh no!
Six HP.
180 gold.
I feel like if I find a portal, it's just...
Time to... Oh no, another one.
I'm gonna TNT him.
I don't care.
Got him!
This has been crazy.
Okay.
Keep going.
Get that.
Got a wand here.
And an enemy.
What is it?
Burst of air.
I'll take it.
Okay, I think it's time to get out of here.
It's a bit sad, but we'll have to do it.
Okay, finally.
Let's see.
What do we got?
I almost can't afford shit.
I can afford this.
Which is... I'm not quite sure.
This one has a bunch of stuff on it, though.
Can't afford that.
Let me actually check the perks.
Sometimes the perk can determine what I want.
What?
No.
Close call?
Uh, no.
Stronger hearts?
That does seem good.
Vampirism.
You lose 25% maximum health, but can replenish health by drinking blood.
Blood doesn't affect satiation level, and you no longer suffer from food poisoning.
Doom!
Isn't that insane?
I have to take it.
It's okay.
If I can fucking restore, that's insanity.
I wonder if that 25% less health is going to apply down the line when I find more health.
Like, let's say I find 25% more health, will it be less than that than I actually get.
I guess I'll have to see.
This one seems pretty cool.
I like that.
But this one has a lot of stuff on it, and it's cheap.
I could get this and this one over here.
Oh, you know what?
Let's do that.
Yeah.
This one doesn't seem worth it.
Let's get this.
Replace it.
Uh, let's see here.
Uh...
That one?
There we go.
This one seems better.
Oh, but it's shuffling.
I don't like that.
I don't like shuffle.
That is a thing I dislike.
Because then I can't put an actual order.
Shuffle, yes.
I mean, this one...
Shuffle...
Actually, the first one is really good.
Maybe it is okay for...
If I just do this...
What's that gonna be like?
Damn!
Oh my...
Dude, that is actually insanely good.
Wow.
Such a small cast delay.
And I guess I could throw this in here.
Even if it's shuffled, it's just sometimes gonna do more.
Burning trail seems like a bad idea for this one.
What about this?
Just throw some air in there.
No, that's gonna set everything aflame if there's fire, right?
Wow, that's a sick wand.
I like that one.
That's gonna be my primary.
Very cool.
Dynamite is cool.
I like dynamite.
Maybe that's better on this one.
Ironically enough.
Wait, type passive?
Lights your wand right up.
This could be useful in that really dark area.
Maybe just having this on my wand will actually...
well, light up a larger area around me.
It may set things on fire though, that's the thing.
But still.
This one has very low cast delay and reach...
not very low, but sort of.
We could probably do some funny stuff there, but I have more money.
Let me try this.
There we go.
That is the glitter bomb.
Some is a bomb that explodes into volatile fragments.
Let's just try that again.
Right, it's that sort of chaotic stuff.
Not bad.
It's not gonna destroy any of the environment though.
That's a bit sad.
But it's pretty cool.
I guess.
And you can really spam this if you need to.
On that one, maybe I'll have...
That's actually pretty nice as it is.
That's not bad at all.
In fact, how does this look?
Yo!
That's actually better than this.
Wow!
Yo, this one is sick!
Do I want this one or that one?
I probably want the burst of air.
It's too less damage, but it goes farther.
Right?
So that's nice.
And this one can be a...
Oh, but it's only gonna shoot one spell though.
Oh no no, it's actually just there, passive.
Oh yeah, nice.
Oh, but wait, if the torch is there...
I thought maybe I could make the burst of air fiery.
I guess it's sort of...
Yeah, I can set myself on fire pretty easily with that.
Let's not, but what if I do that?
Fuck yeah!
Hey!
That's awesome!
Hell yeah!
I think I'm gonna rock this outfit.
This is good.
I'm happy with this.
Let's go!
All spells refreshed.
I have this crazy wand.
Yeah, I'm ready.
I'm so ready for the coal pits.
The air feels extr- oh!
Oh, so I understand what that means now.
It simply means that I'm always gonna be affected by wet clothes, which is awesome for me.
But if I'm in a very hot area, it's gonna be really difficult to get wet.
Makes a lot of sense.
So much money already.
That's a stone.
Blah blah!
Lovely physics.
Just great.
I love Finland even more now.
I mean, I love them already so much, but now it's so much more love coming their way.
Why is it so quiet here?
No explosions, no enemy, no bullshit.
What is happening?
This is very unusual.
Never mind.
I just heard that- oh, okay, here we go, here we go.
Oh, but look at this!
Wand in action!
Amazing!
Tell me that's not incredible.
So much money already too.
So here's a new strategy for exploration.
I'm gonna go sort of around the edge of the area first, and then fill out the middle.
Yo, this is great.
This is a great wand.
Let me also try this a bit.
Look at all that slime.
It's a shotgun, man.
Oh, wow!
He died instantly!
How is that not- okay, okay, it's gonna burn.
Ah, that's nothing here.
What do we got up here?
I was like very slow shooting, so it's not actually that great.
Definitely like this one better.
What's that?
A dead enemy?
Oh, a wand!
Yo, what?
Triple spell?
And a bunch of lightning bolts.
I have to try this.
Say what?
Whoa!
Oh, that feels good.
That feels powerful.
Damn.
Can I hit myself with it?
I don't think so.
Let me try.
Never mind.
I can hit myself with it.
That's good to know.
But long range?
Okay, it doesn't actually go super long, because it explodes halfway.
Yeah.
I guess it's one of those, oh shit, wands.
I'm gonna save that for a rainy day.
Let's just say that.
Actually, don't save it for a rainy day.
That would be the worst time to use it.
Electricity when it's raining?
Not a good idea.
Who are you?
Yep, give me that money.
Kill that guy, grab that.
And then we murder this fellow right there.
There's a girder.
Wait, how is this a rock?
That makes no sense.
That's definitely not a rock.
What are you?
Like a little dude with a bomb.
Little dude with a bomb.
Shit!
Oh no.
God, I love this wand.
I made something great here.
Keep going.
Oh, that was close.
I heard the loading of the weapon.
I was about to eat some lead.
There's a spawner somewhere.
I think.
I didn't expect that to hit me from that distance.
The spray.
Uh...
That does not ignite it, but this one does.
That sound effect is so satisfying.
Money!
I actually killed something there.
Whoa, what is that?
It's a mega dude with a mega gun.
I'm mega scared.
Is he not burning at all?
Oh, shit.
Damn, dude.
I'm about to die.
Yeah, it's over.
I knew Roboticuta.
Nah, the portal was right there as well.
That's so unfortunate.
Well, that was a solid run, though.
I want to say that was good.
That was good.
Uh-huh.
What the fuck just happened?
Something exploded and now it's raining.
The hell just happened?
Wait, what is up there?
There's something above me.
Uh...
Hold on.
Oh, what?
It's raining from further up, too.
Where's that coming from?
Oh!
Hello!
Oh, almost got that icicle in my head.
Jesus.
I want to take my way in there.
Nice.
Not bad.
Nice!
Hold on, I have an idea.
So there's a bit of a delay... a little bit of a...
Ah, I thought I could sort of...
recall my way up there.
Wait a minute, why is this so...
Aw, man!
Shit!
That's gotta be a way.
Mud Potion.
Okay.
What if I just hold it?
It takes me to there.
Let's do a bit of a...
more tapping here.
It takes me the same amount, it seems.
Okay.
Fuck!
How do I get there?
I need to... oh, I need to do something like this.
Ice.
Can I freeze the ice in the air, somehow?
Hold on, I have an idea.
Oh, we're gonna bake... we're gonna make a mound.
Make a mound!
Yes!
Lots of mud!
Fuck yeah!
The mud is the answer!
I'm the mudman!
Emerald Tablet, Volume 1.
It is true without lying, certain and most true.
That which is below is like that which is above.
And that which is above is like that which is below.
To do the miracles of one only thing.
And as all things have been and arose from one by the mediation of one.
So all things have their birth from this one thing by adaptation.
What the fuck is this writing?
That is so obscure!
That which is below is like that which is above.
Is it saying there's a mirror world?
Hold on.
Secrets of endless lava have been unlocked to you.
Sea of lava, summons a large body of lava below the caster?
Sure.
Let me get that.
Hold on.
Wait a minute, let me get up there.
I could...
Have I angered the gods?
Uh oh.
I think I could technically...
around there.
Yeah, easy easy.
What is this place?
Brickwork.
Is there anything else up here?
Doesn't look like it.
Hmm.
Weird.
So I found a spell.
I kind of want to try that spell here.
Maybe that's going to do something.
This is just ice.
Put that there.
I'm going...
My curiosity is rewarded!
Huh?
I got a hundred gold.
Cool.
Alright.
I was about to just leave it behind because it's kind of useless but I guess not.
What the fuck?
I'll take that.
Uh, back down we go.
That's fucking awesome.
Okay.
How weird is that?
I kind of want to try bringing more things there now.
Actually there's multiple of these places.
Wait.
Uh...
Wait a minute.
There is.
There is!
The boss!
Also I didn't even check what I had.
Sparkbolts, right.
I'm going to try this at the boss.
Whoops, give me that.
Ah, come on.
I need to find some water ASAP.
Okay.
Let's not get impatient.
It's at this point where you start to be a little impatient.
I like that.
Chaotic Polymor...
Mmm.
I do wonder if some of these transformations will allow me to fly.
So I'm just a sheep now.
It's not going to help me.
Stay in the polymorphine.
Fill me up before I go go.
Actually let me make a little bath.
Oh shit!
Molotov!
Awesome!
Oh, but now my chaotic polymorphine is burning.
Dang it.
Alright.
It's kind of cool that I can transform into random things and then get random abilities.
That is a very unique ability.
Oh my god, will you die?
Asshole.
Get him.
What else we got?
I want to go up there.
I need to find maximum HP thingies.
That's what I want.
That's a dead end?
Or is it?
Burn!
Open up!
Let me through now.
Take it easy.
I think the reason I did so well on that long run is because I was very patient.
So I need to do that again.
Doesn't that kind of look like a flag on the golf course?
We've got a shaky screen.
There we go.
I definitely want to go to the boss area again.
If I can find a crazy wand in here, that will do a lot of damage.
I am going to try and take on that boss.
Defeating that boss will probably give me something insane.
At least I can only hope.
Because that seems like a tough challenge.
Gotcha, there's another one here.
Take care of you.
Let me grab that gold before it disappears.
Thank you.
Let me kill these guys down here.
There's a shotgun man!
Let's take him out with one shot.
Come on.
Walk back here.
Oh, there's a guy coming.
Looks like he's not going to walk back down here.
That's okay.
I'm just going to take these...
Oh, here he comes.
Shit.
Shit, now everything's burning.
Ah, fire's spreading to me.
Oh!
This little piece of shit is annoying me.
This little area here, I can't...
Is he drinking that?
I'm just going to join this guy.
In the bloodbath.
There we go.
A little risky, but it worked out in the end.
Not bad at all.
Wow, what the hell is happening up there?
Oh, it's oil!
I see.
That looks dangerous.
What the fuck?
Now it's toxic sludge.
I made a mess here.
I made a real mess.
Let's open up and accelerate this a bit.
The fact that you can do this...
is really cool.
In fact, let's just open here.
Come on.
Man, it stopped right after I went through.
That's incredible.
Should've waited a millisecond more.
Not that I got hit or anything, but still.
Can I please get a wand or something?
I don't have a coffee if I'm going to get a drink.
There's a dude up there.
Headshot!
Sniper man.
What is that?
Nice.
Very cold and calculated.
Just the way I like it.
This was the area where everything blew up in the beginning.
And we saw it from upstairs.
Shit was on fire, yo.
He's going to be on fire in a moment here.
Because that's coal.
And he's sitting on it.
It's going to be a very slow death.
He's going to see it coming in good time.
But he's just going to stand there, I guess.
Let me accelerate that.
I have no...
Okay.
I don't know what I am, but I like it.
Whoa!
What just happened?
Is that a type of enemy that just explodes?
Because if that's the case, now I know about it.
And when I see these guys inevitably, I'll know to avoid them.
Or at least get close to them.
I have a magic.
You know what?
We're going to go up here again.
Let's see if this same place is there.
And can I...
Do I have mud again?
I have swamp.
That's not good, though.
Can I bring a rock?
Oh, this is a big...
Oh, hold on.
Yeah!
I think we can definitely make it.
Oh, it came to me!
Familiar orb of true knowledge.
You reward it with additional health.
Fuck yeah!
Oh, shit.
Damn it!
What is the shaking?
I wanted to make a little ledge to stand on, but I don't think I managed.
Oh, I actually did, I think.
Almost!
Okay, so tapping quickly is not the way.
You gotta hold it for longer.
Yeah, definitely.
Oh, I slipped!
Hold it for like a second every time.
That's the way.
It's too slippery.
If I can stand there a millisecond, I can get the rest of the way up there immediately.
Yep.
There we go.
Is it the same?
Yes.
Let me try and go up here again.
Let's see if the same thing happens.
Fuck yeah!
115!
Okay!
So it's every time.
Very nice.
What a nice little secret.
That's gotta be a secret.
I'm gonna check on the progress screen next time.
If my secret counter has gone up.
I think I found three last time I checked.
And I'm not sure what qualifies.
But this has to be one of them.
Finding a bit of gold like that?
Here we are again.
Back in the mines.
Familiar sight.
That is acceleration!
I do love me some acceleration.
It fills me with determination.
I mean acceleration.
Go here.
Wait, did I just?
Oh yeah, I crit.
Okay.
That's why I one-hitted the dude.
Whoops.
I'm gonna go all the way to the right.
In hopes of getting to the lava area.
Why is that spinning?
It's spinning back and forth.
Look, I'm not moving.
It's automatically.
That's interesting.
Get out of here!
Whoa!
Okay.
Okay, then.
Hello!
That works wonders.
Oh, all the toxic shit.
So the magic missile is incredible against those floaty boys.
Is this actually gonna damage me, the flammable gas?
Come on, let me test.
Oh, my O2 goes down!
That's a great touch.
Okay, good to know I can't take damage from this.
What?
Did I?
Wait, is it right?
Oh, it's right there.
Wow.
Bye-bye.
So effective.
Look at all that gold!
Oh, it's catching fire.
That's a little bit sketch.
Do it anyway!
No!
I was greedy!
I thought I could survive!
I couldn't.
We gotta save that one.
That was a terrible death.
Honestly, I did not see the acid.
I did not.
I thought it was just...
I don't know.
In my mind, I remember just before that the green stuff didn't hurt me.
So I was just like, okay, it's just the fire I have to worry about.
So if I just touch the green, I'm good.
Unfortunately, the acid is real and the acid is bad.
So yeah, there's that.
That was a funny death.
Wait, is it night?
I love that the things change.
Like the weather, the time of day, the layout.
It's always a little bit new.
I could go up again and grab that upgrade, but I'm not gonna actually.
Oh, shit!
Oh, that's poison!
That's not water!
Don't bathe in that!
Flammable gas potion!
Oh, man!
What is this?
The unstable crystal.
Okay.
Yeah, don't pour flammable gas on yourself.
That's a terrible idea.
And now I'm flaming as well.
I was just about to douse myself.
Ah, no.
I need water ASAP.
This is already a disaster.
This will do.
Okay.
Basically what I'm looking for now is something great.
Like a wand or something where I know it'll be good.
Like a good run.
And I'm not impatient.
See, that's what I'm talking about.
Fuck yeah.
Let's blow that up.
There we go.
It shall burn.
Actually, it's not gonna make it.
Try that again.
Wow, it doesn't catch fire because it's made of steel!
So I think we gotta come from above!
There it is.
Just like I planned.
Let's get out of the way there.
Yoink!
That's mine.
125.
That's the surface.
Yo, you could technically make a quick route through here.
Let's do it!
Yeah.
Nice.
Beautiful.
I don't even care.
We're gonna go through here.
Just for the lulz.
Okay, that explosion is not effective.
Honestly, it's not gonna...
I need to go this way, sort of.
And that's not happening.
I can't really launch this crystal up there somehow.
If I find a bomb, I'll do it.
Okay, we're fine.
That is flammoxium.
Sir, would you like some flammoxium on your clothes?
It's all the rage.
Oh, you're dead.
Thank you.
And his corpse has now been dissolved in acid.
The standard way of disposing of corpses.
Flammoxium, sir?
Care for some?
What does it do?
Come on.
Get flammoxed.
See, I'm flammoxed now.
That's not the idea.
I want him to...
Oh my god, this is impossible to control.
Flammox!
Okay, stop fucking around.
We're gonna kill him now.
I do wanna experiment, though.
Oh, this is catching fire.
He did.
Ah, here we are.
This is the spot.
I almost got hit by that falling debris.
So, dude, I'm gonna take this.
And bring it with me.
I do not have acceleration, though.
I actually don't have shit.
I can't cross.
I need some of that good stuff first.
Also called water.
That would also do the trick.
Got him.
At least there's a little delay between their jumps.
So, if they jump once, you know you're safe for at least a couple seconds.
Probably one second.
Let me
kill you.
77 gold so far is not terrible.
It would be better.
Man, I'm stuck, I'm stuck.
Not bad.
I think I... Did I already find some extra health?
I'm not sure I did.
Maybe that was last time.
Uh, Berserkium?
Douse.
Shit, that's poison.
Don't douse yourself in that.
I keep doing it.
Berserkium is on me.
Got him.
Good.
Everything's burning here.
Seems like something exploded.
Nice.
My god!
I could not hit you at all.
This guy is a Figured Piper Berserkium!
Oh, there's a bunch of it here.
That's why.
And a wand!
Don't mind if I do.
Wait a minute, more enemies?
No.
What is this?
Woah!
Luminous drill with timer.
Sparkly bounce.
Uh, there's a bunch of those for some reason.
Let's try this.
Oh my god, this is terribly useless.
Huh?
Weird.
Yeah, that's weird.
But maybe I can use that later.
There's gotta be a way to really supercharge that...
drilling spell there to make it somehow insane.
I would love that.
What about the Berserkium?
What is this?
Cannot pick Kyu- Kyuaskivy.
Please- Oh!
Uh...
I'll get rid of...
honestly this one.
What the hell is this?
This tiny rock looks most fiery.
But when touched, only a pleasant warmth can be felt.
Ooh, looks like an egg almost.
What?
Oh yeah, it's flamy.
What if I throw it?
It is now in the Berserkium.
Maybe that will do some damage to the enemies.
If I hit them with it.
Probably gonna set things aflame, isn't it?
Dude!
Maximum health just hanging out there.
Cool!
I love that.
Let's see if we can hit somebody with this.
What if I throw it hard?
Nothing?
Oh, definitely...
So it's basically a...
flammable...
thing that is fine to hold.
Which is kind of cool, I guess.
I still haven't found what I need.
Which is water or some kind of accelerant?
Or maybe even the...
Woah!
Uh oh, yeah, I touched this.
Maybe don't have it on hand.
Played a bit safer here.
Oh no, this is a bad spot for me.
Can I hit it from here?
You missed!
Somehow I took damage just now.
I don't know how.
But I did.
Alright, flaming egg time.
Here you go, buddies!
Yeah!
Set them all aflame.
Oh, it's not actually doing much.
Give me that.
Okay.
What if I shoot you with this?
Oh, right.
That's one of those.
Whoops!
Give me that money.
I see you there.
Thank you.
In fact, I'll take this.
No, the other way, the other way.
Oh, I have to point that way, of course.
Never mind, they're dead.
I'm gonna hit this guy with a missile.
That's not a missile!
Burn.
Oh yeah, he burned it.
Bye-bye.
Look at all that sweet gold.
But, there's a bunch of acid.
Let's hover it right above it.
Oh, that was risky.
I'm on fire now, I'm on fire.
Fill me.
Oh no, that's Confusion.
Oh, I'm an idiot.
The Confusion completely messed with me in my panic moment.
I wanted to get in the portal.
But my character kept running the wrong way.
Fuck.
Oh, shit.
My plan was to go through the portal and jump in the water bath on the other side.
As quick as I could.
Shit.
Man, oh man.
I will release the worm again.
Because I need to see something.
I want to see if it's a different worm every time.
And maybe if I'm lucky, it'll be a friendly worm.
I still have hopes for that.
Boop, boop.
And then if I find the worm pheromones, I'm going to try and guide it where I want it.
It's a big if, of course, but could be cool.
Nice.
Got it.
Let's go.
In fact...
Oh, dude.
If I get to the boss, I'm going to release this Kraken right next to the boss and hope it just destroys it.
Wouldn't that be cool?
Who knows?
Maybe it one shots it or something.
It's sort of RNG the way it moves, right?
So if I can find a way, a place to hide while that thing does its job, that could be cool.
What do I have?
A single spark bolt and unstable crystal again.
So many times with the unstable crystal.
We're going to be ultra patient this time.
Hey, sir.
You almost hit me there.
I love the way he's bleeding.
You know, you make a small hole in him and he bleeds the acid.
That's so cool.
Last time there was a minecart here.
I pushed it in and I couldn't enter because I blocked my own way.
Give me a beer.
What if I just destroyed completely?
Wow, this thing is doing a great job holding in the liquid.
Right now it's, I believe, water.
Um, I'm drunk AF.
I don't think that's good.
That's like a negative status effect.
Not a positive one.
The outside is right there.
Motherfucker, you hit me.
I could probably launch that there and give it the old attack.
Hello, it's working.
The whole tree fell down.
Hey, I made it.
Look at this.
I escaped the mines.
Let's explore this way a bit because I believe there is an upgrade you can get over here.
And then I'll come back.
There's a floating piece of dirt.
There.
And you know what?
Let me go on top of that.
That seems interesting.
It's nothing.
Well, okay.
Not bad.
What is here?
It's the ocean.
Um, dude, it's actually night now.
How cool is that?
I kind of want to have a torch or something now.
That would be cool.
Is this thing still down here?
It is.
What the hell is that?
That is so mysterious.
Doesn't that look like some kind of musical instrument?
I'm going to try and destroy it again.
All my projectiles are being slowed by the water.
It made a sound.
You hear it?
Wait a minute.
Last time it exploded, I think.
If I remember correctly.
Oh man, it's taking all the damage here.
I'm cutting pieces of it.
I mean, the fact that it's taking damage, damage numbers, means it's going to...
There was another big boom in the distance.
Like a rumble.
Okay.
Why is this not happening?
Wait a minute.
Wow!
Okay, so that...
Is that an enemy then?
That counts as an entity of sorts.
Or not.
I don't know what's going on there.
It's a mystery to be sure.
Let's see what's over here again.
I think there is an orb somewhere.
And the good thing is, we can get back to the mines really quickly because of that little path that I carved.
What is this?
Right.
Wet clothes?
What is
this?
Rock?
It's just rock, this is ground, and that's soil.
Okay, I'm walking quite far.
Okay, so this is the desert.
Hello!
Oh!
Ah!
Fuck!
I'm on fire.
What the hell is that now?
Meat?
It's bleeding, look!
Oh no, the tree is on fire.
Oh, I can't even get past this.
Exquisite me?
My goodness.
That's for you, sir!
Wow, what a shot!
Damn!
Well played, sir!
There was a particle coming from upstairs as well.
I think someone was flying above me.
Ah!
At least I fucking got you, motherfucker!
That's right.
That felt good.
I think we have to go try Matilda again.
I didn't actually release the worm.
I'm gonna do it now, though.
But here's the thing, I'm gonna go into the mines, and I'm just gonna let all hell loose with the worm this time.
I want the worm to just clear everything for me.
Kill everything.
Clear all the paths.
Basically do my job for me.
That is the new plan.
Got it.
This is gonna be great.
It's gonna be amazing.
You know what, I'm gonna try hard so hard now.
Oh, I can't actually go on top of the mountain this time.
Because I don't have the right bombs.
I can't make a little path up there.
That's unfortunate.
Although...
That is a want.
I could maybe...
Yeah, let's access from here.
Look at that!
And then we have exactly what we need.
This thing will make a hole like no other.
Scrap!
Look at that!
It's raining again.
But why is it only raining in one spot?
That makes no sense.
Oh, it's cause it's water falling?
Question is, can I make it up high enough?
Is this...
It's mud.
Oh my god.
The gods are on our side.
It's mud time, baby.
Mud me up!
A
lot of mud, a lot of mud, a lot of mud.
Okay, here we go.
One second.
Oh, I have to destroy this.
That's right.
It's gonna fall down on me.
Beautiful.
Okay.
Let's just continue now.
125 max health.
This is a great start.
And we have the worm.
It's gonna be chaotic AF and it's gonna be lovely.
I'm just gonna enter from here now.
Why did everything just shake?
I don't like that.
Okay, it's time.
Matilda!
Oh!
Ah, what a shot.
Off you go.
It's a small one.
Got him.
I mean, it's gonna dig, but it's not gonna be a big one, but that's okay.
Hopefully, it'll... is it gonna die in that acid?
Give me this.
No, no, no, no, no.
Mud me up.
Dead end.
Look at all that water rushing down.
Because it's raining?
That's gonna create a big pool of water somewhere.
Down the line.
What do I even have?
I have bombs and that.
Okay, yeah, right.
I love that when you shoot these enemies, they start bleeding in the areas you shoot them.
And if it's blood, it's like... well, it's blood, right?
But if it's acid, they start leaking acid.
That's... that's like... I've never seen that before in a game.
Like that.
It's really cool.
There's a party going on down below me.
Why am I going into the oil?
Nobody knows.
Wash me off.
In fact, let's replace the mud with the water.
We don't... we don't want mud.
Mud this area here and then grab water from here.
Mmm, fill it up.
There we go.
Maximum water.
This is a... okay, so this is a great start so far.
52 bucks in the bank.
And 125 max HP.
And we're chilling.
We even have a magic missile we can utilize.
Exquisite me, sir.
You are unable to jump in this water.
That's awesome.
That's good to know.
But I'm flammable now and that's a risk.
So I need to douse.
A bit more.
There we go.
Play it extremely safe.
I intend to get far.
And find secrets.
I want to find out more about the lore.
I want to learn about the art.
I was spoken...
Wow, what a shot!
That was a headshot.
Okay.
There's a guy on the left.
I do love the minimal usage of music in this game.
Not that it's bad music, you know?
But it's like Minecraft in that way.
Wow, he didn't even die from that.
Excuse me!
Stop!
He's going to kill himself.
That gold nugget was weirdly square.
There we go.
Bathe me in blood, look at this!
And I think we have arrived at this spot.
Awesome.
We're going to try something now.
Take this.
I'm going to make a little path here.
Hopefully we're not going to fall in.
I fell in accidentally one time.
That was scary.
Oh.
Oh, the rumbling!
Oh my god.
Oh, this is so scary.
I'm going to fly the rest.
I believe!
Oh, fuck yeah.
Made it.
Okay.
So there was a bit of a pedestal over here as well.
I'm going to try and put the tablet on that now.
That's probably going to do something different.
Or maybe it's just going to give me money again.
Actually, oh, there's a tablet here as well.
I forgot about that.
Thank you.
So if I now do this...
Maybe it needs to be on top of it.
Wait a minute.
Then again, this is yellow.
This is green.
The other one up top was green.
Oh shit, here we go.
It's time to avoid...
Oh wait, it's going to be difficult to get back.
Just do it.
Holy shit!
Wow!
Okay!
New rule.
Man, he has a wand.
We are setting up a new rule now.
If I ever go for this, I need to have accelerant on me.
Otherwise, I just can't get back.
It's insane.
Or at least the chances are very low for survival.
This motherfucker, I want to kill him so bad.
I want to see what happens.
Unstable crystal, but spitter bolts.
Let's stick to the basics now.
No more bullshitting around.
I'm not going to go to the boss now.
I will, you know, do the stuff that I know works.
Which is just collect some gold.
Go through the portal.
And make a great wand.
And I want to find more spells as well.
So far, all the spells have been really cool.
In fact, I want to find that one rain spell again.
Because I'm curious how that's going to vibe with other combinations.
Like, how can I make that do something insane?
Maybe I can make it rain bombs.
You know?
All these combinations you can make are insane.
Yeah!
Why is that beer thing shaking?
Hello?
Why is the beer wobbling?
It's burning now.
That's some demonic shit right there.
Good thing it's burned.
I wonder if you could pick these up.
You know, take them with me and throw them around.
Okay.
That's a dead end.
I'm like, what was up with those plants suddenly appearing?
In the middle of the level.
And then, now I haven't seen them in a while.
Yoink!
Grabbing that.
Hops!
God, this is a good weapon.
The one-shot potential.
Oh, it busted!
Got him.
That was it.
Better.
Nice.
Okay, so far so good.
We lost 4 HP to that.
That is acceptable.
Green slimy meat.
Can I eat it?
Let me first put some water here.
I'm sick.
Ingesting green slimy meat and more.
I mean, to be expected, I guess.
But you never know.
Water it.
Pee on the enemies.
It's always a good strategy.
That's a nice trick.
No wait, that's a good trick.
That's what he says.
In that one movie.
With the little kid in the spaceship.
He didn't die from that.
One down, two down.
One shot, one kill.
Two shot, two kills.
Oh yeah, that's for you.
A wand.
What do we got?
Slimeball.
That's the same projectile those green slimy meat boys.
Or emitting, I believe.
Yes it is.
And it does a crazy amount of damage.
Because it explodes.
Oh yeah, so it actually does.
Uh...
What?
There's a wand, embedded in the rock.
Look at that.
I can't get to that.
I don't have the means.
I have this.
Boom!
Why did that explode so quick?
Alright, I'm gonna leave.
This is too dangerous.
I have deemed it so.
We have to follow protocol.
And protocol is...
Uh...
Play it safe, play it slow.
And never take risks.
What's this?
Magic missile, lovely.
I like that.
That means I can actually go back here and get to that wand.
Hello!
Imagine if that wand contains something insane now.
That would be the story of a lifetime.
Ew.
Um...
Let's not get stand to...
Oh actually, it's sort of burning nicely here.
I do like the burning.
But I'm gonna stand here safe distance.
Scrap!
I missed.
Shit.
Got it.
Okay, so I can stand a little bit closer, I think.
There we go.
Yes, dig it out.
There it is!
Okay.
The all-seeing eye.
Utility.
So that's a type in itself.
It's not passive.
It's a utility.
Wait, damage?
Drill?
Why is that a stat?
What does that even mean?
This one has a very short cast delay.
Is this wand good though?
250 max max?
I don't even think this is that good.
I'm gonna keep this because this has insane stats here, doesn't it?
Then again, this one does too, but it only has one slot.
And it shuffles.
But that's okay, if I can put...
...spitter bolt in here, that would be really nice as well.
I'm gonna leave it.
I don't want it.
I refuse.
But now we have peace of mind knowing that there was nothing insane in that wand.
And that makes me happy.
Do need to collect some more water though.
You know, blood is just the same as water, except with a bit more...
...kick, you know?
Just grab all this.
Wait, why am I taking damage?
You can still fit...
What is... hold on.
Satiated 31%.
I do wonder what that even means.
Your stomach is almost empty.
What is the point of that?
Bloody clo... you sense an incre...
Oh, this is actually just...
Okay, so blood is actually just better water all around.
I kind of forgot I read about that.
Increased chance of critical hits?
Hell yeah!
Blood me up!
Not that I need to crit against these guys.
These are just critters.
And I'm a critter.
But a different kind of critter.
Blip!
Alright, we've been doing well so far.
Let me grab that gold.
166 gold, that's nice.
We're doing really well.
Let's keep exploring.
Yapsie!
Good.
Nice.
And there's a dude up here.
Let me take care of him.
Needs a stern talking to.
There we go.
How about you?
You up for debate?
Oi!
Sick.
Why is everything burning there?
I should stop asking these questions.
Everything just burns in this game.
Everything explodes.
Violence everywhere.
Look at that!
I killed the guy.
He slid off this plate here.
And collided with a lamp that fell and caused a huge fire now.
This is the sort of shit I live for.
I love it.
Oh, I'm stuck here now.
You know what that means.
It's diamond time!
Blip!
Blow that shit up.
We do that again, because that was fun.
Hell yeah.
Carving a path.
And there's an enemy.
He's gonna catch fire now.
Let's just wait for him to die.
In fact, I can go here and be relatively safe.
In fact, I'll fill up my water bottle.
There we go.
And the guy died.
And all these beams are burning.
There's a chest!
Fuck yeah!
I'm not risking that gold.
Let's just wait for this to burn.
In fact, I could piss on it a little bit.
Yeah, don't burn the chest!
I need more water.
Oh, wait.
Huh?
Uh...
Ukuskivi.
What the hell is that?
This small rock makes you feel very charged.
Okay!
Interesting!
So I can...
electrify things.
Let me grab it again in between charges.
Yuck!
There we go.
I'm gonna take that with me.
That is very interesting.
I wonder how I can utilize that.
I did find another rock that...
did something when I kicked it, remember?
I think this is in the same vein as that.
Okay.
Why do I hear moaning?
It's not as intense as in that other place, but it's there.
And I hear it.
I've seen everything.
There's gold!
Oh, it's gone, it's gone.
Uh, gold here, I'll take that.
And we've got a bottle!
A worm pheromone!
Okay, I have to go back and grab the worm now.
We have to try this experiment now.
Also...
Oh, that's just one of those enemies.
That looked a little scary.
It's really nice that these small ones also drop ten gold every time.
Oh, that's...
I gotta go out and grab that worm.
It needs to happen immediately.
Go here...
What do we have up here?
Uh, not much.
Back to the entrance.
And that is right here.
This is one of the few times when you can actually go back to the start.
I wonder...
When I'm here...
Oh, I cannot...
change my wants.
I think it needs to be in that...
place.
The Holy Mountain.
Okay.
And now it's night.
We spent a nice day in there doing important things.
I wanna try and mix chemicals...
with powders.
Something just exploded.
They're still having fun in the mines.
This is what happens when you play patiently.
Almost max HP.
Everything's going great.
It's a lot of fun.
Yuck.
I have an idea.
Let's just try this.
It's blue, right?
Just like this altar.
Will it reward my curiosity?
Come on.
What if I piss on your altar?
Oh, it's catching electricity now.
That's dangerous.
Rabbit.
I will not pick that thing up.
No, no, no, no, no.
Oh, I love this soundtrack here.
It's like, fills me with dread, but it's also mysterious.
Makes me want to explore more.
That's the best.
267 gold.
That's solid.
We could purchase some good stuff with that when we get to the Holy Mountain.
The Holy Mountain.
Doesn't it kind of look like the wheel of this wheelbarrow is a face?
Mouth, eyes.
A smiley face.
Fuck you.
Oh, doesn't even work.
I have to kick it from this side.
Six skateboarding tricks.
Okay, so watch this.
I shall release the worm, but you know what?
I'm going to wait a bit.
Because I'm going to get to the portal first.
Just to have an exit if shit goes wrong, okay?
If I'm about to release the mother of all worms, I want to be able to go through that portal ASAP.
So that's the plan.
Kill that guy.
What's over here?
I need to explore everything.
There's nothing.
Water bottle.
Fill me up.
Fill up my belly with water.
And we got that shit.
Some uranium waste.
Oh my god.
We're about to have a party here.
Watch.
Hey.
Hey dude.
Fuck me.
Oh!
I did not expect there to be an enemy.
But there's a bunch of gold.
I'll take it.
I'm not going to take that gold nogget, because I am patient and I am risk averse.
I shall take no risks.
Except I just sort of did.
But that was a fun risk.
That's different.
Why is there a piece of wood here?
That's mysterious.
I don't like that.
I do like the water here though.
Oh!
That was the collapsed mines?
That little area.
Now I have to get in there.
That's four... I can make a path.
Whoa!
Hello.
Ah, you did.
Love this one.
You know what?
This spell right here is actually insane.
What is the difference between the normal mines and this part?
I don't think I've noticed that yet.
Really.
That's a...
What's happening?
Who is throwing bombs?
We've got moaning again?
That's definitely a sign of bad times.
Uh-oh!
I'm gonna lure him into that.
Watch.
BAM!
He didn't die from it.
He died now.
Fuck yeah.
Yoink!
Wait, what is this?
Oh, that's just a skull that's left over.
Very neat.
Let's blow this up too.
Whoa.
Wow.
Didn't expect that to take one shot only.
He probably took some damage from the previous explosion.
That's for you, sir.
Hey, go!
Hey, you, go!
Hey, you, fuck!
Yeah, that's fine.
Let's blow it up.
It's so good.
You're dead.
He threw dynamites.
We are okay.
Don't even think about it.
I'm on fire.
Get in the water.
There we go.
Beautiful stuff.
Grab these before they disappear.
And there's the portal.
So that means it's time to release the Kraken.
Sort of.
Oh man, I'm getting greedy now.
I'm getting greedy again.
It's a bad sign.
There's more enemies.
I need that gold.
What is that?
Rusted metal.
We hate that.
That's damp rock.
What does that even mean?
Can we blow it?
We can.
I'm gonna drain this and let this guy flow down into the blood.
And then I'm gonna execute him down there.
That should send a message.
Exactly according to plan.
Almost.
There we go.
Execute it.
Don't you just love it when things go according to plan?
Hold on.
That looks interesting.
Blow that open.
Let the water flow.
And then I will flow through.
Because where does this lead?
Oh.
Interesting.
What do we have there?
Hold on.
I need to drain this water more.
Let's use some of these crystals.
Damn.
Okay.
Oh no, it's not blowing up anymore.
I need only dirt.
Let's try again.
No, it's not.
It's not doing it.
Maybe this stuff down here.
No, that's extremely dense rock.
That's not gonna work at all.
Ah, shit.
That's a mystery for another day.
Oh, actually it's not.
It's time to release Matilda.
Oh, not that one.
Here we go.
Where's the portal?
It's right down here.
Okay, so here we go.
Let's see how this goes.
What's my escape path?
Probably to go up here.
And no, actually just go through the thing.
But I kind of wanted to dig on the left.
Go!
Okay, it's a small one.
Where are you going?
You saw a bit of corpse falling down there.
It's Matilda's younger sister.
Sort of chilling.
What if I kill it?
I'm gonna try and kill the worm.
Holy mountain.
Wait, if I'm here technically now...
Okay, I can't change.
I'm gonna try and kill the worm.
It's a boss fight.
What is that stuff down there?
I think Matilda's younger sister is off somewhere.
But this is a good spot to jump in.
We did a lot.
Fuck yeah!
That was a good first part.
I'm proud of myself.
Full health?
110.
Ah, we can buy a bunch.
I don't want that.
This, I don't know.
Wait, what are those?
X?
The hell is that?
Oh wait, I know what that is.
No, I don't.
Hmm.
Wait a minute, what perks do we have?
A Loki minion.
Summon a Loki minion to your health.
High mana, low capacity.
Your currently held wand loses half its capacity but gains more mana.
Oh.
All seeing art, you can see...
What?!
Yes, please!
The issue with that though...
is that I can't tell where I've been and where I haven't been.
But!
It will reveal secrets such as this.
Oh no, I should have waited with my worm thing until I got here.
Maybe this would have done something.
The worm crystal.
But whatever.
I think I may want...
Let's see here.
Are any of these good?
The thing is, I'm not sure what constitutes good yet.
Like, not entirely.
I think I may want to try this one.
Change it with...
That one?
Let's see.
Summon hollow egg.
Summon an otherwise empty egg that casts a spell upon cracking open.
Like a kinder egg.
You never know what you get.
Bloop!
What spell was cast?
It didn't crack open.
Come on.
Hmm.
Okay.
That's weird.
Damage melee?
Thirteen.
What?
Okay, that's weird.
Let's try another one.
Oh, I don't have enough.
Oh, I have enough for this one.
Yeah, let's do it.
Formation bifurcated?
Cast two spells in a bifurcated pattern.
The bubble spark.
That's actually really nice.
The sparkly bounce.
Makes the projectile release damaging sparks as it bounces.
So...
You know what?
I actually have a...
Oh.
I do actually have a crazy wand.
Is it this one?
Uh, no.
It's actually this one that I have on me right now.
This one right here is actually insane.
Because look at the cast delay and recharge time.
If I were to put this one in here...
instead.
Let's see how fast that is.
Holy shit!
Whoa!
Okay, that's way better than I thought it would be.
Damn!
Oh!
That's crazy!
Yo, I like that.
I like this a lot.
That's the ultimate shotgun.
Oh, wow.
Okay, uh...
I'm gonna keep that for sure.
This one though...
I can combine it, I think.
This is a modifier.
If I not...
Okay, wait, wait, wait.
What can I do?
Sparkly bounce on the magic missile, maybe.
Actually, try it on this first.
Cool!
How much does it do?
Oh, it doesn't say how much mana.
Damaging sparks?
It doesn't say how much.
Bounces plus one.
Only when it hits something.
Will this damage me?
Wait.
Huh, I'm not sure.
Doesn't look like it even explodes when I do it next to me.
It's like...
It has to go a certain distance first.
Weird.
But okay.
And then we have these two ones.
This one has a very low cast delay as well.
In fact, what if we were to do this?
Actually, that's not gonna do anything, because it only casts one.
This one has 0.07.
0.03.
That should be even f...
No?
Okay.
Because the recharge time is so big.
Right.
So if I instead had a bunch of spitterbolts I could put in here, that would make the difference.
The fact that the recharge time on this is so low, that's what's doing it.
Good.
I am very slowly starting to master this game.
As you can tell.
Let's try this.
That is indeed bifurcated.
I don't like it though.
What if we bifurcate some crystals?
Seems dangerous.
That only shoots one.
I don't like bifurcation then.
0.83, 0.45.
I think this one is better for that.
What does it say?
Oh, I don't have enough mana, I think.
56 maximum mana, that's nothing.
So it works here.
So this, what does this do actually?
Oh, you can't shoot, oh, because it's a modifier.
So you need something to carry the light, right.
That's not bad.
That's a nice little light you can throw.
I mean, I'll use it.
Maybe even with that.
Maybe I do like this more then.
Yep.
This is a good setup, I'm ready.
I am friggin' ready.
Let's eat this thing over here.
Blop!
Spell's refreshed.
And now we head into the coal pits.
The fuck just happened here?
Something just exploded.
I love this effect.
Everything is collapsing behind me.
Wow, right into it.
Nice.
Good thing I was ready for that.
That would have been a disaster.
So I want to use this.
Let's get it, ooh.
That thing.
Cut it.
Destroy it.
Let all the stuff drip down on my enemies.
I'm on fire!
Whoops.
Damn.
Wow!
Holy shit!
I love it!
It's a machine gun.
Machining Gewehr zweionfüzeck.
MG42.
I'm blasting everybody with this.
Watch, I'm gonna kill this guy with a stone.
Oh no, come on.
Cut it!
Shit!
My plants.
Oh my god.
Get out of here.
This is getting a little too risky.
Oh my god, the mana recharge is super slowly.
I just noticed, that's a bad part of this.
I need to be conservative.
Give me gold.
Let's get rid of that.
Come on.
Down you go.
Oh, you're about to get fucked.
I love this.
It's a great game.
Can I stand on this one?
I can!
Watch this idiot throw himself.
Oh my god, I'm hanging on!
Barely.
Jesus!
Is this bad?
I'm okay.
Oof.
Okay, okay, okay, okay.
So we found the portal already.
That was quick.
Not bad.
Why is this still going?
Nothing just exploded.
Okay, so this is charging, using mana very fast and it's charging slowly.
I did not think about that.
So that's the trade-off there.
But I guess it's good in a pinch.
What the fuck is that guy wearing?
That's some kind of fucked up wand.
I'm gonna shoot him with this.
Sir, come here.
Oh, I thought he would drop.
Okay, he's shooting flame balls.
Bam!
Right in the face.
Show me what this is.
Firebolt.
Nice.
Um, do I want it, though?
0.07 and 1?
Hmm.
Instead of this one, maybe.
This one only has some...
Mana max 1-7.
I think it's better.
Oh, shit.
Wait, what?
It's bifurcated, but it shot three there.
Look!
Two spells in a...
Oh, wait a minute, because it's...
I understand why.
Look at the burning wheel!
Cool!
Burning wheel is gone.
It's because it's shooting bifurcated, but it's shooting multiple spells at the same time.
And one of those spells is just a normal spell that goes straight.
That's what happened there.
That is what happened there.
I actually do not like this effect of you can see everywhere.
Because I don't know where I've been.
I've definitely not been here, though.
I'm gonna grab that.
That's for sure.
But this is gray rock.
Can I get through it?
That's a Colvane?
I can get through that.
That means we're going to the other side.
Let's go to that!
Don't you bomb me!
There we go.
What the hell is this?
Did a plant just grow in his...
The place where he died?
What the hell?
That was weird.
So far we're playing good, I would say.
This is solid.
It's crystal time.
Again.
Crystal time is... three.
Ah, shit.
It needs to be closer to the edge.
It is the third one.
And I can't be too close, though.
There we go.
Lodge to perfect link.
Look at that.
Professional gameplay on display here.
Got it.
135.
Don't mind if I do.
Nice.
Come here.
Oh, there's two of them.
Oi!
That was almost bad.
He's dead.
He just damaged himself.
What a silly goose.
Thank you.
Bunch of water there.
Makes me want to grab three bottles and fill them all up with water.
And then use those bottles to fill up my tummy with water.
There's nothing like it.
What is that?
Teleportation!
I've appeared somewhere...
Whoa, what?
I picked up max health somehow.
I teleported onto a max health, I think.
What is happening?
Oh my God.
Whee!
Ah!
Oh!
It's chaos!
What the fuck?
Huh!
Stay here.
Man, teleportation.
You don't fuck with that.
That was nuts.
Yeah.
Don't.
I'm not going to do that again.
I'm going to do it in controlled bursts.
And that means drinking it.
I'm going to fill up my belly with teleportation.
There's gunpowder and acid over there.
Um.
I have to try.
Cool.
Ah!
I'm poisoned.
Fuck off.
I'm actually almost dead.
But I know where there's a portal, approximately.
So we are actually okay.
That guy's dead.
Mission successful.
Look at all that gunpowder.
Ooh.
Hoo hoo hoo.
Definitely.
Ooh.
Hello.
Wait, you can teleport.
Come in here.
He has a green wand and it's dripping with green stuff.
Does that mean he's making some kind of...
He went over here now.
I'm going to gain access.
Burn the beams.
In fact, I'm going to hit him with this magic missile if he comes close.
I don't trust my machine gun that much.
Where are you?
Oh yeah, look at that stuff.
Looks cool though.
Oh!
Does he got on the left?
There was two of them.
Sirtariamastari.
Shit.
I gotta save that one.
Look at this.
I was totally focused on the guy on the bottom and then this guy.
Did he teleport in at the last moment?
Look, he's not there.
Poof!
He flanked me.
He teleported in, flanked me and shot my ass.
That's amazing.
Well played.
I have to save that one.
We gotta save that.
That's incredible.
Okay.
God, I want to keep going.
It's actually been...
Oh, it's actually been seven hours almost.
I'm gonna do one more run, I think.
Or maybe a couple of more.
I don't know.
We'll see.
I just really want to keep going.
It's too much fun.
What do I have?
Water.
Okay, perfect.
I have sparks and I have bombs.
A classic.
And the air feels hot this time.
Which means it's gonna be hard to get wet.
I was kind of caught between a rock and a slimy place there.
I'm gonna go up top.
I need to find Wands.
That was a bit of a panic there.
It happens.
The surface is right here.
I would love to dig through that right now.
I do wonder how many biomes are in this game.
I wonder how far I am.
I think I got pretty far last time.
Well, not last time, but the one time where I got really far.
When I made it to the dark place.
Ooh, look at this.
Wow, there's a wand in there.
Those fuckers.
Well, I'll take you up on that challenge.
I'll bomb the shit out of it.
That's right.
This is steel, unfortunately, so that's not gonna burn.
So I may have to drop another bomb on that.
Shit, I'm burning.
Water me.
Did I make a hole at least?
I think I did.
Ah, it's burning now.
Can we just wait?
What is that?
Hold on.
Oh!
Bro!
Stop slipping.
Qs... Oh wait, I have had one of these.
The pleasant warmth.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Okay, it's just a torch.
I'll take it.
Bakers can't be choosers.
I am so glad for this wand.
Thank you very much, game.
I have pre... What is this now?
The hell is that?
Hmm...
It's a water barrel.
Ow!
Oh shit!
Oh my god!
That was a trap!
They distracted me with the water barrel!
Bro!
Got him.
Let me distract you with a water barrel.
There you go.
You're so mystified.
Oh wow!
Yeah, I'm playing Risky now.
I'm not following the tenets!
Oh!
This guy's a beast!
Get him.
There we are.
Man, this wand sucks.
I want the puffy balls again.
Those make me happy.
I'm gonna go right.
I shall risk it for biscuits.
I feel like if I'm at this stage where my health is low, it hasn't gone super well.
I may as well be a little risky.
I am gonna try and go...
Whoa!
For the... I don't want to say boss, but I'm gonna get that upgrade and get the fuck out of there.
What the hell is happening?
He's trying to kill that guy.
Look.
Another one of these barrels!
Kill him!
And a beer barrel!
I can kick it!
What if I bring beer to the boss?
Maybe he'll be happy about that?
Can I pick up this thing at all?
I can kick it.
I have very good strength in my leg.
Oh wow!
Calm down.
Nice crit there.
We have arrived at the spot.
So I have a way to get across.
But it's a little bit risky.
But you know what?
This run is risky at this point anyway.
It's fine.
Keep walking.
I have no fear.
No fear.
And then we go.
Smooth operator.
That's what I am.
So the thing I need to do now is get across really quick on the way back.
And just as soon as I get to this point, I just need to go up.
So that when he shoots a projectile, it's gonna burst over here on that wall.
That's the plan.
Maybe... I don't know if it's time-based or when I come here that he comes up.
I think it's when I arrive here back, then he comes up from the depths.
So yeah.
That's an issue.
Okay.
I got it.
You found a familiar orb of true knowledge.
There's no way to get out of here otherwise, right?
All right.
Hold on.
Can I...
This is yellow.
How about we put this here?
That was a rumble.
I think it was incidental though.
It was a coincidence.
Give me that.
Okay, we gotta be quick.
I will throw this at his face.
No, I'm gonna just go.
Ha!
I'm a sheep!
Fly, little sheep!
Run!
Come on, come on!
Fuck!
Man, that shot!
Look at that shot!
Zoom!
Wow!
I should have jumped.
I thought I was sort of safe behind this little area here because I thought he was down here.
But he was actually up there.
This motherfucker, I'm saving this.
Ha ha ha ha!
That was funny though.
So he turns me into a sheep, huh?
That bastard.
I need to kill that guy.
I have to find a way.
And the only real way to do it, as far as I know, is to somehow get a crazy wand in the mines.
Actually, that's not true.
If we can get to the snowy depths again, we know there's maybe a way to get back up here, right?
Because that leads down to the snowy depths.
So if we by that time have some way of coming back up, then we're golden.
We have Swamp Potion.
I love Swamp.
It's the inferior water.
And we have this nice weapon now, so that's good.
That's a plus!
Good.
Already making good bank.
What is that?
What the hell is that?
Oh!
God damn it.
I should have known.
I hate that.
I mean, I love it, but I hate it.
You got me.
You got me, game.
Good job.
So there's always new things.
That's actually really nice.
What just happened there?
Something just exploded.
I wonder if the enemies can walk on those mines.
Funny thing is, that mine looked exactly like something you would see in Worms.
You know the little mines you can drop on each other in that game?
Something like that.
Can I shoot it?
Wait a minute.
There's two of them here.
Let's try.
You definitely can't...
Fuck, you scared me.
Okay, good.
You can shoot them, and they're very visible.
Shouldn't be a problem.
Let's get through here.
I feel good about that explosion.
That explosion filled me with excitement.
Oh, don't walk into that.
Blow it up.
Okay.
Keep going down.
Oh, fuck.
Dude, I'm on edge right now.
Bro!
Okay, he has a long range shotgun somehow, and I have a shitty range shotgun.
Hmm.
Yeah, there we go.
That's what I need to see.
Ha!
It bounced on the roof and hit him in the face.
That is glorious.
Now we are bloody, which is nice.
But it is extremely dry, isn't it?
It's very hot in here.
So, actually not that great.
Let me get through here.
I'm using my bombs a little bit willy-nilly right now.
But I think it's okay.
Got him.
Drive by shooting there.
Wow, that was so smooth.
And we got a wand!
Fuck yeah!
How do I get that?
I know how I get it.
It's easy.
Just go along here.
Shit.
I got him.
Okay.
What was that sound?
Hello!
Wasn't that a much larger explosion than normal?
Why did that just happen?
Okay.
Always casts S30 mana.
That's awesome.
Luminous drill.
Let's try this one.
How much drilling is happening?
It's like, not bad.
Hello!
That's not bad at all.
Look at this.
I can live with that.
Whoa!
That was sick.
And he's burning alive.
Let's wait for that.
Money.
Oh shit!
I'm on fire.
Pssst!
Swamp water.
Uh...
Swamp water!
Got it.
Okay.
Good to know I can...
The collapsed mines.
Is there something special going on in this part of the mines?
Invisi...
Invisiplium potion.
Oh shit.
Oh!
Oh no, it's one of those guys.
What the fuck?
Is this water, isn't it?
Oh fuck, it's not!
Oh my gosh!
It's lightning.
I understand now.
The cloud is red because it's bad.
It's not green or blue.
It's red.
It means...
Not good.
Fuck.
Okay, that's sick.
That enemy is insane.
Ah, fuck!
Motherfucker!
This game keeps throwing shit at me.
But I'm just out here with my tennis rack.
And I keep bouncing shit back.
And I'll keep doing it.
Entered mines.
I like how I said at the start of the stream.
I'm not gonna die a single time today.
See how that went.
Purifying powder pouch.
Not bad.
Let me put that there.
That's like my powder keybind.
Health!
Oh, that's a great start.
Fuck yeah.
This is actually amazing.
And this...
Oh wow.
Does it get better than this?
Huh?
What do we got?
Bubble spark?
Let's try it.
Hell yeah.
I like it.
Let's dick the shit out of this.
I'm gonna do it from the right.
Ah, I should do it from the left because the enemy is on...
Oh, he's going to the right.
I'm gonna wait for him to come here and then I'm gonna blow him.
There we go.
Burn alive.
Yep.
Give me that money.
Wait, what is this?
Berserkium.
Shit.
It's not water.
Go.
Ah, I got it.
Shit.
I'm burning.
Don't Berserkium.
I'm gonna burn alive.
I have no water.
Psst.
It's not working.
Berserkium makes it worse.
Somehow.
God damn, I lost 30 HP from that.
But we got extra HP, so I think that's okay.
You.
I don't dare go near that.
I don't want to lose another 30.
No, sir.
That's not happening.
I am playing...
What the hell is this down there?
Oh, it's just a wheelbarrow again.
Oh!
Come here.
God damn it.
They are not to be trifled with.
They can pack a punch.
Ah, nothing here.
Kill that guy.
Man, I want to fight more lore.
I want to know about this world.
Tell me about the art.
Tell me about gold and silver and what's up and down.
What's that?
That's...
invisiblium.
The magical liquid on your clothes makes you invisible.
The spell is disturbed by stained or wet clothes.
Wait, there's no way I can just shoot like this, right?
No, okay.
Wait, can I?
Holy shit, wait.
No way.
No, he sees me.
No?
Wait a minute.
I'm not like transparent now.
I am now.
Oh, okay.
So it comes back.
Dude, that's sick.
I gotta... I gotta take that in my flask.
But for now, we're gonna use...
So we have to empty this first anyway.
May as well use it on this.
Persecium.
Okay.
So, okay.
The air feels light.
The hell does that mean?
Maybe it means gases float to the top easier.
Something like that.
Also, I'm very slippery.
So there's a potion up there.
I want to grab the invisiblium.
I think in the collapsed mines is where we find that enemy that fucked us up last time.
That is the place where he hangs out.
This is very precarious.
So, wait a minute.
We need to empty this.
Let's put it in a little bath.
Somewhere, so we can actually get it back if we want.
Fill this up.
A nice berserkium bath.
Here we go.
Now we grab all this.
Oh yeah.
Fill me up, baby.
Come on, come on.
Grab it all.
Good.
That's decently full.
Now we have it on command.
And we're invisible right now, too.
Let's wait until this thing...
There we go, we're invisible.
Dude, I could scout the entire map if I wanted.
Let's shoot them both.
Oh, sick!
Wait a bit.
Nice.
And then we kill this guy.
How do you see me?
I'm invisible.
Oh wait, I'm not.
It must have run out right then and there.
Oh, shit.
We've got one of those guys.
I'm gonna blow him up.
Have fun.
Yeah!
Oh god, oh god.
Oh god!
We gotta take care of the small enemies first.
If they're there.
Shit!
Let's bomb him again.
Fuck you!
That was satisfying.
Jesus.
Give me the gold.
Okay.
It's a good start, I think.
235 and more to come.
I'm gonna be a little bit more greedy.
If I encounter the bad dude, the badass, we're turning heal.
And running.
Just run away from the danger.
Blow the rape whistle.
Hope somebody comes to rescue us.
That is the plan.
I want to kill these guys.
Get that sweet money.
This is like the easiest area, so I really should try to get as much money as I can from here.
Why is this coal all bloody?
A massacre happened here.
I've been here, but I also haven't.
How do I get down?
I don't.
Damn it!
Go around.
Shit.
Close one.
Here we go.
Oh, I can't get up there.
It's okay.
Is the guy about to appear?
Oh!
Motherfuckers are scaring me.
Oh my god!
I'm starting to feel less safe.
You know what?
I'm invisible.
Fuck you!
Got him.
Sort of.
Oh, I don't have any more bombs.
That's unfortunate.
Let me be more invisible.
There we go.
So this green stuff won't hurt me if it's in the air.
Okay.
There we go.
Oh.
And there's still a dude with a shotgun.
Oh wait, I need to be invisible.
Look at that.
There we go, dude!
Very nice.
Shit, I accidentally fell in, but that's okay.
That's okay.
Probably for the best, honestly.
Here.
135.
That's good, that's good.
I have three wands and some spells to choose from.
What the hell is this one?
This looks interesting.
Electric torch.
Energy sphere with timer.
The hollow egg.
Triplicate bolt.
Explosion!
Just straight up explosion?
Static projectile.
Huh?
Infinite uses?
What?
Wait, I'm scared.
Is this gonna explode right on me?
I'm gonna go in the water.
Oh my god, it is!
Fuck me.
Yeah.
Okay.
Wait, static projectile?
What does that mean?
How do I utilize this?
Uh...
Spitter...
I like chain bolt.
I actually like that.
We're taking it.
Let's see, chain bolt?
Yeah, dude, this is great.
25 damage is nothing to scoff at.
Uh...
I'm afraid of testing with this.
Shit.
Castellae...
plus seven...
.75.
So...
This one...
would be the best for that, I guess.
Yeah.
Oh, but it's...
slow recharge.
That's actually not good.
Also sort of slow?
Let's try...
Wait, where did it go?
Oh.
Let's try this one, see how fast that is.
That's better.
I may use this one then.
But we also have other things.
Fire trail...
bifurcated.
We could have two chain bolts, I guess.
Or even this one.
We gotta try this.
A triplicate bolt.
A formation of three small fasted bolts.
Oh wait, this is a spell in itself.
Oh, okay.
Oh, that's a shotgun.
Fuck yeah.
That seems lovely.
I like that.
Maybe I'll put this here instead.
And what else can I get?
It costs a little money for some reason, all of this.
Spitter bolt.
No.
Electric torch.
Gives your wand a bright but very dangerous light.
Oh shit.
All right.
Oh wait, that's not as fast though.
That's better.
Let's leave this one here.
The chain bolt can stay on this one.
What else do we have?
Maybe I do want this then.
Use this here.
Why does this not work?
Oh, because it only casts one spell.
That's why.
If this casts two spells, it would be a different story.
Actually, no, no, no, no.
I'm misunderstanding this again.
I need to have two spells here.
I keep misunderstanding this bifurcated.
If I had a spell here, that would put the other one on the other side.
That's what's happening.
So look.
See?
Yeah.
Perfect.
I understand.
Let's see the perks.
Angry ghost.
An angry spirit comes to your aid, copying nearby spirits.
That seems dangerous.
Projectile repulsion field.
Most projectiles are repulsed by your presence, but you take slightly more projectile damage.
Hmm...
I don't know about that.
It would depend how much repulsing we're talking about.
Gold drop by enemies, explode when it disappears.
Oh yeah, okay.
Man, I don't know.
How about we try...
this one.
Let's see how good it is.
Protectile repulsion field activated.
Oh, it's only within this little sphere.
Huh.
Okay.
I can keep buying.
Energy sphere with timer.
Why would I ever want a timer?
Is the question.
Wait, energy sphere?
What is that?
Energy sphere.
Oh, it's that one.
Okay.
Cast another... So wait.
Cast another spell after a timer runs.
So if I do...
Wait.
Wait a minute.
I think I understand.
Luckily, it happens over here.
So if I go like that...
I'm testing!
Wish me luck!
Yeah!
That's awesome!
Dude!
How about this?
Oh wait, doesn't...
80...
No, I have enough mana.
Huh.
Shit!
Why did that happen?
I don't understand.
God damn it.
Is this not... Can I not trust this?
Oh, okay.
Never mind.
Wait, why is it doing this now?
Oh, I'm using the... I'm an idiot.
It's this one.
I'm dumb as fuck.
There we... Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
I'm an idiot.
Oh my God.
I'm just gonna sit here and wallow in my own...
Stupidness for a second here.
God damn it.
You live, you learn.
I forgot about the fact that this only worked because there was a timer on it.
Shit.
But this is cool.
Look at this wand, man.
How is that not amazing?
And how much does this do?
68 damage!
Holy shit!
I'm in love.
We could even egg it up.
Let me get another one of these.
Spitterbolt, Skeldor.
Get rid of that one.
Maybe I do just want this and that.
Wait, why is it...
Why is that so inaccurate?
Wait.
Is my own field repulsing my own projectiles?
No way.
That's horrible.
I think I like that more.
Do I?
Yeah, I think I do.
Or although...
No, I'm gonna have this one.
Oh, yeah, that seems sick.
Let's try that.
We're gonna run with this setup.
Let's go.
Lost a bit of HP there, but it was all in this in the name of science and figuring things out.
And it's right.
That one is dangerous.
Don't use it close quarters.
That's the thing.
Yeah.
Okay, let's go.
The cold pits.
We are back, baby.
Can't wait to see how this field is working.
Oh, let's go.
Whoa.
Quadruple scatter spell?
Cool.
How does this work?
Sparkly bounce with bubble spark and trigger.
Okay.
Wow.
Cool.
I mean, I like it.
I'll take it.
Because I had an empty slot anyway.
Now that thing is bad.
So let me just cut that off immediately.
Off you go.
Explode somewhere down there and poison enemies and all that.
Give them uranium poisoning.
And now it's just a vat of acid.
Awesome.
Ah, what do I have?
I still have invisiblium in my bottle.
Fuck yeah, the shotgun.
Watch.
Holy shit, it's good.
Lovely stuff.
I'm too afraid to jump in and grab that gold.
Not that gold, that's fine.
Let's try the big ol' explosion wand now.
Ah, that is a bomb.
Bam.
Yep.
Hello.
You are going to be the test subject for this one.
Oh, sick.
Oh, yeah, baby.
You didn't even die from that.
Where'd the other guy go?
Did he die?
Oh, I can't get past.
Give me gold.
Oh, yeah.
I managed to get it.
Sick stuff.
I haven't really noticed how this repulsion field has helped me yet.
Have fun.
I see some gold.
I do not want to grab it.
We're played safe.
Stick to the tenets of the Master Wizard.
He taught us three simple rules of this world to survive.
The first one being, always go before you leave home.
Meaning, to the toilet.
What the hell is going on up there?
Second, play patient.
Third, don't take risks.
This is about to burn.
Oh, no.
I'm caught.
Fuck you.
I can shotgun.
I have to go quick.
Shit.
I'm burning.
I'm burning alive.
Water, water, water, water, water.
Oh, man.
That was a spot to be in, huh?
Very scary.
We may have to start looking for that portal.
And I say may because I actually don't want to.
I want to keep going.
I want to be greedy.
No, stick to the tenets of the Master Wizard.
We go deep.
We look for portal.
And we do it slowly and patiently.
Get rid of that.
Fuck you.
It's a great wand.
It's so good.
Wait, what?
I didn't have enough mana for the explosion.
Man, that guy has HP.
Ahoy!
I could have gone bad.
A plant just fell from the roof.
Hello.
Bye-bye.
That crit too.
Major damage.
Please hit someone in the head.
Yuck.
There's the portal.
We have our exit.
Sir.
There we go.
Beautiful stuff.
Ah, man.
I don't know.
224 gold?
That's not a lot.
It's not.
It's not a lot.
It really isn't.
Let's try and get just a bit more.
Just a taste.
Oh, what's that?
No, that's the lava dripping thing.
We don't want that.
You know what?
Fuck it.
We go.
I believe.
I believe we get sick upgrades now.
We have 38 HP.
We have to play it safe.
The tenets of the Master Wizard shall be obeyed.
Let's see here.
Vertical barrier!
They exist!
Oh, that's the spell that killed me!
Thundercloud!
So I know what it does.
Oil cloud!
Double spell!
Spark bolt with timer!
Magic missile!
The glittering field?
Reduce spread.
Formation above and below.
Oh, so like, cool.
Let's check the perks.
Breathless.
You can no longer drown and can move in liquids with ease.
That's actually pretty cool.
More blood.
Blood, blood, blood.
What?
I gotta try it.
I'm too intrigued.
Blood, blood, blood.
More blood.
Just more blood.
I mean, if there's more blood, I can get increased crit chance.
That's something to consider, right?
I have 224 monies.
I am tempted to go for the double one.
That seems cool.
Yoink!
Let's try it.
Spell.
So if I now do that...
How double is it?
Oh, that's pathetic.
Wait.
Huh?
Simultane...
Oh, I need two spells in that slot, I guess.
Huh.
How is that different from...
I guess it's not.
It's a little... This one just separates them, right?
So that's the disadvantage on that one.
Okay.
Got it.
So, bubble spark with trigger.
How would this look like?
They cast another one when they hit, right?
Not bad?
Yeah, I don't know about that.
I don't know about that one.
Ah, let's buy some more.
Maybe...
Wait, spark bolt with timer.
Ooh.
This one actually is kind of sick.
I think.
You know what?
I get the vertical barrier.
I think it could be cool.
That's my explosion.
This one is...
No, I don't like this one very much.
Oh, wait a minute.
What's this?
Simultaneously cast four spells with low accuracy.
Right.
Nah, that's fine.
Put this back here.
Maybe it's a bit of a waste to use this one there.
0.18, 0.37.
Oh, nice.
Manamax 360.
Yo, this one is better in all respects.
We should do this.
That.
No, wait.
That's not going to change anything.
Wait a minute.
Wrong one.
Is it?
Hold on.
Let me see the board.
Two spells.
One spell.
Hmm, why is it doing that?
Oh, I think I understand why.
So, it shoots one spell per cast.
Right?
The first spell is that one, called double spell.
And that double spell shoots these two.
And then the next spell is this one.
So that's one.
And the next spell is this one.
And then it starts over.
This one is simply these two together.
That's all that means.
Watch.
Two.
Wait.
One.
Two.
Oh.
Oh, wait, it's shuffle.
Oh, god.
I see.
Shit.
Okay, this one does it the way you expect, I guess.
But is it actually... I feel like this is better?
Is it not just better?
That's... crazy.
I mean...
Hmm.
Let's try this one.
I mean, you know what I like about this?
This is just my shotgun now, right?
But then, at times, it will just shoot this one, too.
And fuck it, if it hits something, that's great.
If not, that's also fine.
So that's the way I see that.
You know?
Let's just do that.
That seems good.
That seems real good.
We can also try something like this.
Wait a minute.
That's a multi-cast... Can I stack multi-casts?
I'm gonna drain two...
I'm not sure.
That's better.
Bum, bum, bum.
Cool.
I like it.
But then there's also the trigger one.
You know what?
This could be really cool.
Oh, wait.
It's not doing what I think.
Okay, so if I hit them with this, that's gonna trigger at the location.
So maybe instead of that, I want something that can go a little farther, like this.
Like that one.
Oh, wait, wait, wait.
No, it has to be this one, because that's the one with the trigger.
I'm an idiot.
Shit.
But I mean, it can still hit something.
That's a mess of a spell.
You know what?
I love it.
Yeah, that's cool.
Let's run with that.
That's awesome.
Let's go with that.
And then we have this guy.
Barrier.
Wait, why did that go up there?
Oh, is it where I aim?
Huh?
I would think that would appear right in front of me.
What the fuck?
Hold on.
There's a bit here at... What the hell?
Okay, I don't understand that.
Never mind.
We're not doing that.
That makes no sense.
I don't get it.
Let's just have fun with this.
Protectile.
There.
Modifier.
How about that?
Yeah, that's cool.
Better than nothing.
And we have no more money, so we go.
In fact, we recharge and then we go.
There we go.
Spell refresher online.
We have four bucks to our name.
And that's it.
Okay, I think my main thing is going to be...
Whoa!
Two and three.
Snowy depths.
That one?
That one.
Those are the two main ones I have.
And also...
That one is cool as hell.
A wand!
Immediately.
Chaotic path.
Immediately I'm intrigued.
I'm not intrigued.
Back!
Okay, let's see what happens now.
Upside easy.
We've got enemies.
Oh, yeah.
Oh, Jesus.
Oh, that's a good one.
That's a good one.
Hello.
Oh, my God.
Oh, actually, it does deflect the Protectile's look.
It's super good.
My repulsion field.
Oh, it's super good.
I love it.
Look at that.
Heck, yeah.
I feel so cool.
Killed them all.
In cold blood.
Literally cold and blood.
Look at this.
All right, give me...
And I guess there's more blood now.
Blood, blood, blood.
So it would be cold blood, blood, blood.
To be exact.
Is it deflecting?
Oh, it's also deflecting those.
That's sick.
Fuck you.
It's gonna send it back.
Return to center.
Hey, that's awesome.
Fuck you.
Oh, okay.
Let's not be too...
You know.
Let's calm down a bit here.
I do love diamond.
There's a bunch of diamond here.
Eat it.
Oh, my God.
I can't hit anything.
Freezing vapor is bad.
Don't go near it.
Just wait for it to pass.
Wait till all this blows over.
Eat the diamonds.
Yum, yum, yum, yum, yum, yum.
What is the point of eating?
I don't understand the whole satiation system yet.
I need to experiment a bit with that.
I eat snow.
You're feeling cold inside.
Movement is difficult.
Cost ingesting snow and more.
Yeah, so why would I do it?
It's bad.
Don't do it.
Don't even eat it.
Okay.
I want to try and get to the portal in here now.
That's my mission because last time I never made it that far.
I don't think.
I got to this scary dark area.
What the hell was that?
A huge gold nogget.
I want fire.
Oh, no, this is... oh, no.
Come on, cold, snow, eat the snow.
Oh, that works, I think.
Eat the snow.
Bye-bye.
I can't even get in there.
That's a trap.
Is it not?
Does this explosion even...
It doesn't even go through.
Oh, that's a bummer.
I may have fucked up here.
I have no way to get in.
Unless I can grab it through the wall.
Come on, come on.
Shit, I can't.
Let's try again.
No, no, this is made of steel.
Even though it looks like wood.
The repulsion field, man.
I'm so happy I tried that.
Yeah, that blood is very electric.
I was quick around the draw.
Bro, this one right here, sick.
Yeah.
That's a hand.
Wait, is it moving?
The hand is moving.
Shoot it.
Again.
The hand is becoming smaller.
The hell is happening?
I don't even want to know how many times this repulsion field has saved my hide.
Look at that beautiful freezing vapor.
That is actually beautiful.
Jesus.
I have a feeling my repulsion field is not going to do shit against this guy.
Oh my God, he shoots through the snow.
Thank God I one shot him.
That could have been a disaster.
Okay.
Wait, I can get through snow though.
Yeah.
Cool that the snow melts and becomes water.
You know what?
Invisible.
They're fighting each other.
I joined the fight.
What?
He sees me.
There's a sniper on the right.
Ah.
Where are you?
Reveal your precision.
There you are.
Fucker.
Uh oh, uh oh.
Oh, it's a duel.
Got him.
I'm in the pipe.
Shit.
Oh my God.
I'm beset on all sides.
Run.
Fuck me.
I'm dead.
I'm so dead.
We got to leave.
Got to leave.
Get the fuck out of here.
No, no, no, no.
I don't want to deal with that.
We leave.
Jump.
My goodness.
We made it.
At what cost though?
Holy shit.
I have no money to my name.
I can't even purchase any of this.
I can...
buy a bomb cart.
What?
What's this?
Plasma beam cross.
Oh man, there's so many cool things.
I can purchase oil.
Summon firebox.
Oh my God.
What perks?
Show me the perks.
Lukey minion.
Gas fire.
Gas scenario ignite.
Projectiles slower.
Dude, in combination with the repulsion.
Projectiles near you slow down.
Fuck yeah.
We got to try that one.
Look at these two barriers I have.
That's awesome.
I shall be unstoppable.
Okay.
We move on.
I'm curious to see what's next.
Did you see the sign it makes when this thing...
when the red circle appears?
Almost looked like a musical note.
Wonder what that means.
Oh wait, I have been here.
This is Heezy base now.
Oh shit, this is where I died.
Last time I tried hitting one of those energy thingies.
And I have a theory that it reflected the spell onto me and I died.
Because of that.
What the hell is this thing hanging there?
Get rid of it.
What's up Heezy people?
Take it easy, okay?
We're all friends here.
Are we though?
Cold plus brass pouch.
Ho!
Excuse me?
Okay, two shots they need.
Wow, what the hell is happening?
A bunch of blood emanated from that machine.
Sick.
We've got floating turtles up there.
Hold on, I can't use this weapon in close quarters.
I need something else.
Uh oh, here comes this cavalry.
One down.
Two down.
Here comes the guy.
Can you make it through?
He can.
Shit.
Oh no.
Kill him.
I got him.
Oh, it's burning.
Get in the ice.
Shit.
Blood.
Bro, this is a disaster.
That's a treasure chest.
Hell yeah.
I can get it.
Yes.
180, baby.
That's big.
I want more treasure chests.
That make me happy.
I have two of these now.
Man, how do I utilize this properly?
67% coal, 1% brass.
Carrying powdery materials.
Can I some...
Hmm, wait a minute.
We shall do some tests here.
How about invisiblium?
And then we pour in some...
coal and brass.
Let's mix in some purifying powder now.
For good measure.
Okay.
It's not doing anything.
Make me invisible.
Oh no, it's water now.
Shit.
Oh no, I thought it was invisiblium.
Wait, that's the wrong wand.
Wait, it's not.
There we go.
Wait, blood appeared up here when I killed him.
What the fuck?
More blood indeed.
Shit.
I crit him.
Oh shit, I'm burning.
Get rid of him.
Kill this guy.
Kill that guy.
Red!
He killed his friend.
This is nuts.
Got him.
Holy shit.
Every one of these enemies explode in a bunch of fire when you kill them.
That is dangerous, AF.
Get some of that money.
Don't get all this blood.
It's a fucking bloodbath.
And I love it.
Fuck you.
Look at all this blood that's coming out.
It's great.
Yes, bathe in the blood of my enemies.
Oh, that's a bit risky.
Red!
One down.
Show yourself.
Come on.
Burn.
I hit him.
One more.
Oh yeah, maximum blood attained right now.
Gotcha.
I missed.
Got him.
Bunch of fire, be careful.
I have to remember this.
Blood me up.
Come on fire, go out.
I need that gold.
Fuck off.
Oh shit.
Got it.
Bathe in blood.
Get him.
This is sick.
Oh yeah.
Lots of fire, lots of fire, lots of fire.
Got him.
This is a sick weapon.
This is actually a sweet weapon that I have here.
I like this weapon a lot.
I really, really do.
Hello.
Is he shooting his friend?
I am so focused right now.
This is maximum gamer moment.
Got him.
And then the fire comes dribbling down.
So cool.
Oh, I know what that is now.
Look, it's totally a mine.
Just like the red one I saw.
With a different effect of course.
I think it reflects.
So I don't know what to do about it, really.
Maybe just avoid it.
Uh oh, I missed.
Oh no.
Oh my god.
I can't hit for shit right now.
It's a duel.
Come on.
Come here.
Oh my god.
Got him.
That was a tough one.
He played well.
Well played, sir.
So I'm not going to go near that at all.
I'm too scared.
What if I throw that in there?
A fridge.
Okay.
Does not want to cooperate.
This thing is hanging up there.
Is this a fluorescent light?
What if I shoot it and then quickly get out of the way?
My escape path is down here.
But there's also this hanging.
Ooh, I don't know.
I'm going to try and shoot it.
Uh, wait.
Let's shoot this one up here first.
I think it's just a light.
Yeah, okay, perfect.
I'm going to try and shoot this now and run away.
Ah, it reflects.
It bounces off.
Oh, that was a sick shot.
I'm a god.
It is known.
Uh, there's nothing here.
This level is awesome.
Can I walk through this, though?
Wait, what?
Ahoy!
This was risky.
I was standing next to this box.
And he could have easily shot that to smithereens and exploded me.
I took a crazy risk trying to walk through this thing right now, but it paid off.
So do I regret it?
No.
I do not.
There we go.
Clean and smooth.
Something shook.
Watch this.
Get frozen.
Get unfrozen.
Hide in the blood.
The blood is where we feel safe.
Is this going to hurt me if I go through that?
And we're fine.
There we go.
God, I love this weapon.
It's a great one, isn't it?
He has a gun!
I guess they have to man it.
Fuck your gun.
Holy shit.
Holy shit!
Take care of them one by one.
I missed.
Get the blood.
Got him.
Oh, this is sick.
This is so much fun.
Come here.
Don't miss.
There we go.
Atta boy.
Yeah.
Oh, I hit myself.
See, that's what can happen if you're not careful.
Got him?
Missed.
There we go.
My God, there are many enemies here.
This is insane.
This place is nuts.
There's a gun there.
Missed.
Is that thing going to explode on the big explosion?
Wait, can I?
Can I utilize this gun?
Oh, it's shooting by itself.
Okay, okay, okay, okay, okay, okay, okay.
Oh, what's happening?
Oh, it's a slippery slope this year.
Get out of the way, get out of the way.
Oh my God.
This is bad.
I'm slipping too.
Holy shit, I'm on fire.
Get to the water.
Get to the...
Yeah, steam.
No, no, no.
Eat the snow, eat the snow.
Shit.
I'm burning.
Get the blood, blood, blood, blood, blood, blood.
Okay, let's just...
What's this?
Piercing shot.
Harmful to the cat.
Facing arc makes objectives fly much slower.
I can't think about this right now.
Focus.
We've got a big boy coming in.
Oh my God.
Holy
shit.
We're so fucked.
Oh my God, this is a disaster.
Look at all the gold pop popping out of him.
Take a bath.
It's my safe space.
All that lovely gold, I'm not gonna get it.
I say no to gold.
I reject gold in this run.
No fucking way.
Purifying.
Purify that shit.
That actually works pretty well.
Sort of.
I wish it would stop burning everywhere.
There's still a thing there.
I got it, I got it, I got it.
Shit, shit, shit, shit, shit.
Oh!
Oh, there's a sniper.
Oh my God.
Oh shit.
I hit you.
Wait, he spawned a bunch?
Fuck, I killed myself.
Oh no.
This place is crazy.
That was a great run though, that was fun.
I got pretty far in that.
I gotta stop now, man.
It's been way too long.
Actually, I don't regret a thing.
Look at all the stuff I found today.
K.K.
Tanki.
Setilasa, Lenoki.
All these Finnish names.
Cool.
Doesn't this progression of enemies right here remind you of the Apes to Man t-shirt a little bit?
The way they... and then more upright?
I wonder if that's intentional.
Look how many spells there are.
I only found 18% of the spells in the game.
What?
I don't even understand how that's possible.
How?
How's that possible?
Goddamn.
Okay, yeah, I gotta quit this.
Holy shit.
Yeah, that's crazy.
Man, I played a lot.
That was great.
Hamis?
Oh, that's the name of the enemy.
The small one, isn't it?
Congrats on Hamis.
Hamis.
Thank you.
Wait a minute, let me put some...
Actually, I cannot put the singing bowls on anymore.
Because I read on their website that it's actually only for personal use.
So, I don't think anyone would ever notice, but I'm not gonna do it.
Unfortunately, the singing bowls...
It's a good one, but...
Can't do it.
Instead, we get to hear this background.
Wind.
I like that, too.
Yeah, I know.
No bowls.
It's sad.
Hamis.
I like how everyone spams Hamis with a thumbs up.
What does Hamis... I gotta figure out what Hamis means.
I mean, it's a Finnish word, obviously.
Or what, though?
Translate.
Hamis.
Luxembourg-ish?
No, it's Finnish, dude.
It means crazy.
Ha!
Hamis means crazy.
I guess they are sort of crazy.
Short for hemisphere.
I'm not sure about that.
No, it doesn't?
Ah, shit.
That's what Google tells me.
I was Hamis once.
Hamis means Spidey.
Oh, fuck.
But maybe calling someone Spidey in Finland means crazy.
I don't know.
Probably not.
I probably looked it up wrong.
Oliver, you don't know Monty Python and the Holy Grail, don't you?
Actually, I do, but it's been a while since I've seen it.
I remember very few things from it.
It's been a long time.
I guess that was a reference in the game that I missed regarding that movie.
They locked me in Heezy Base.
Oh, yeah?
Hamis is a cuter way to say spider, like Spidey.
Ah, okay.
Any Finnish people in the chat?
You should max the replay buffer to max.
Yeah, but it says in the menu that if I do that, there's a chance it may crash.
Is that something you experience if I max it?
I'm afraid of it crashing.
I mean, worst case, I lose the replay, and that's fine, right?
But if it's something that crashes during the game while I play...
Not sure.
I keep it around 45 seconds to a minute.
You know what?
That's a great idea, because right now I have to be quite quick.
Otherwise, I may miss the death, you know?
It's weird that it doesn't start at the death.
Or, like, shortly before the death.
Turning it up a bit is fine.
Okay.
I'll do that right now.
Replay budget, let's put it at...
320 megabytes.
Up from 100 something.
Done.
I have never crashed and I play with mods?
Okay.
Awesome.
Good to know.
I mean, I could also just try it, of course.
And if anything ever goes wrong, I can just put it back.
It's not a big deal.
You did get a revenge kill on that one guy after... Yeah, that's true.
That was awesome.
I think it stops recording when you click to stats.
But I have to click to stats to even click on save recording, no?
Oh, I see what you mean.
I see what you mean.
Sorry.
I understand now.
I liked when Hamis bit you and it really hurts.
Yeah.
That one was a tough one.
That was a bite of all time.
What's your favorite hangover cure, Oliver Stoliver?
I don't know why that sentence made me laugh.
I don't know.
Honestly, for me, a classic is just some junk food.
It works.
For some people, it gets worse if you do that.
Just something greasy, basically.
And then I'm all good.
Something greasy and I'm good to go.
I like when you were confused on what to do with explosion and then figured out what to do with explosion.
Well, if you think about it, it's quite logical.
Obviously, I had to combine it somehow so it didn't explode in my face.
So there's got to be a way to utilize that somehow, right?
I just needed to figure out how.
I knew that it wasn't supposed to be like that, obviously.
That would be crazy.
Unless you have some sort of explosion immunity and you just spam it on yourself running through levels.
I don't know if that's even a thing.
Don't tell me.
Long stream today.
Bro, I streamed early just because I wanted to stream a lot.
Because I couldn't stop thinking about this game and now I got my fill, so that's awesome.
I'm satisfied right now for today.
Yeah, this game is awesome.
I mean, I may fail a lot, you know, but I don't care.
It's awesome.
The Hamis bit is so funny to me.
I love how committed people are to it.
I don't know if you're talking about the bite or the bit, meaning the joke.
I think you're referring to the ladder there.
Artificer build.
Exactly Voidheart.
It's a great game.
It is.
I feel like I have so many great games to look forward to.
Stuff like this, Noita, and Rainworld, and even Hollow Knight, honestly.
They weren't even on my radar before I started doing YouTube and people suggested it to me.
I never really even considered such games as that, you know?
I feel like a whole new world is open to me.
I'm no longer a 2D game hater.
I can enjoy it.
It's good.
Yep.
When I started Hollow Knight, I was a little prejudiced thinking, oh man.
I don't know about these 2D games, you know?
Do you like this new world, Oliver?
I love it.
Yeah.
It means more games to play.
You know what you're going to play after Subnautica?
I'm not sure.
I was thinking...
So I'm bouncing it between a couple things right now that I all want to play.
Prey, from 2017.
I want to try that.
Obviously there's Elden Ring now that the DLC is out.
There's a couple other games.
I forget which ones now.
But I wrote a short list of the ones that I'm thinking of right now.
I'm going to put those that I'm not sure about on YouTube so you can vote on it.